{"id":641,"text":"When the world possesses some great light in any science, every least part is illuminated by its rays, some with greater brightness and some with less; and the miracles that result are also greater or less according to differences of air and place. Constantly, in truth, do we see a particular country producing a particular kind of intellect fitted for a particular kind of work, for which others are not fitted, nor can they ever attain, whatever labours they may endure, to the goal of supreme excellence. And if we marvel when we see growing in some province a fruit that has not been wont to grow there, much more can we rejoice in a man of fine intellect when we find him in a country where men of the same bent are not usually born. Thus it was with the painter Marco Calavrese, who, leaving his own country, chose for his habitation the sweet and pleasant city of Naples. He had been minded, indeed, on setting out, to make his way to Rome, and there to achieve the end that rewards the student of painting; but the song of the Siren was so sweet to him, and all the more because he delighted to play on the lute, and the soft waters of Sebeto so melted his heart, that he remained a prisoner in body of that land until he rendered up his spirit to Heaven and his mortal flesh to earth. Marco executed innumerable works in oils and in fresco, and he proved himself more able than any other man who was practising the same art in that country in his day. Of this we have proof in the work that he executed at Aversa, ten miles distant from Naples; and, above all, in a panel-picture in oils on the high-altar of the Church of S. Agostino, with a large ornamental frame, and various pictures painted with scenes  and figures, in which he represented S. Augustine disputing with the heretics, with stories of Christ and Saints in various attitudes both above and at the sides.","label":[[9,14,"LOC"],[49,56,"PROD"],[93,96,"PRON"],[160,168,"MYTH"],[234,237,"LOC"],[242,247,"LOC"],[274,276,"PRON"],[294,301,"GPE"],[333,342,"PER"],[375,379,"PROD"],[422,426,"PRON"],[457,461,"PRON"],[516,518,"PRON"],[531,533,"PRON"],[554,562,"GPE"],[565,570,"PLANT"],[623,625,"PRON"],[639,642,"PER"],[666,668,"PRON"],[674,677,"PRON"],[683,690,"GPE"],[697,700,"PER"],[745,747,"PRON"],[761,768,"PER"],[761,784,"PER"],[799,802,"PRON"],[807,814,"GPE"],[826,829,"PRON"],[864,868,"GPE"],[864,878,"GPE"],[880,882,"PRON"],[932,935,"PRON"],[943,947,"GPE"],[1006,1014,"PROD"],[1024,1028,"PROD"],[1036,1041,"MYTH"],[1058,1061,"PRON"],[1088,1090,"PRON"],[1116,1120,"PROD"],[1135,1141,"MAT"],[1145,1151,"GPE"],[1162,1165,"PRON"],[1178,1180,"PRON"],[1192,1200,"PER"],[1217,1221,"LOC"],[1228,1230,"PRON"],[1243,1246,"PRON"],[1257,1263,"MYTH"],[1268,1271,"PRON"],[1295,1300,"PER"],[1322,1327,"PROD"],[1331,1335,"TECH"],[1343,1349,"TECH"],[1355,1357,"PRON"],[1365,1372,"PRON"],[1398,1401,"PER"],[1430,1433,"PROD"],[1442,1449,"GPE"],[1453,1456,"PRON"],[1491,1495,"PROD"],[1501,1503,"PRON"],[1516,1522,"GPE"],[1547,1553,"GPE"],[1574,1880,"WORK"],[1576,1589,"PROD"],[1593,1597,"TECH"],[1605,1615,"FAC"],[1623,1629,"FAC"],[1623,1644,"FAC"],[1633,1644,"MYTH"],[1670,1675,"PROD"],[1689,1697,"PROD"],[1741,1743,"PRON"],[1756,1768,"MYTH"],[1756,1880,"MOTIF"],[1788,1796,"MYTH"],[1814,1820,"MYTH"],[1825,1831,"MOTIF"],[1825,1831,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":642,"text":"The pictures of Maestro Marco were executed by him between 1508 and 1542.","label":[[4,12,"PROD"],[16,23,"PER"],[16,29,"PER"],[51,72,"TIME"]]}
{"id":643,"text":"Cola, without caring to see Rome or to change his country, remained always at Ascoli, living happily for some time with his wife, a woman of good and honourable family, and endowed with extraordinary nobility of spirit, as was proved when the strife of  parties arose at Ascoli, in the time of Pope Paul III.","label":[[0,4,"PER"],[28,32,"GPE"],[46,49,"PRON"],[50,57,"GPE"],[78,84,"GPE"],[124,128,"PER"],[132,137,"PER"],[161,167,"ORG"],[243,249,"EVE"],[254,261,"ORG"],[271,277,"GPE"],[279,307,"TIME"],[294,298,"MYTH"],[294,307,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":644,"text":"The same Calabrian also painted in fresco the Chapel of the Conception in the Church of the Trinità, with much skill and diligence.","label":[[9,18,"PER"],[35,41,"TECH"],[46,52,"FAC"],[46,70,"FAC"],[60,70,"MYTH"],[78,84,"FAC"],[78,99,"FAC"],[92,99,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":645,"text":"A short time afterwards, Signor Alessandro Vitelli, who had become Lord of Matrice,[14] took Maestro Cola, now an old man, to Città di Castello, where he caused him to paint in his palace many works in fresco and many other pictures; which works finished, Maestro Cola returned to finish his life at Matrice.","label":[[25,31,"PER"],[25,50,"PER"],[67,71,"PER"],[67,82,"PER"],[75,82,"GPE"],[93,100,"PER"],[93,105,"PER"],[118,121,"PER"],[126,143,"GPE"],[181,187,"FAC"],[193,198,"PROD"],[202,208,"TECH"],[224,232,"PROD"],[256,263,"PER"],[256,268,"PER"],[300,307,"GPE"]]}
