{"id":700,"text":"Jacopo, called L'Indaco, who was a disciple of Domenico del Ghirlandajo, and who worked in Rome with Pinturicchio, was a passing good master in his day; and although he did not make many works, yet those that he did make are worthy of commendation. Nor is there any need to marvel that only very few works issued from his hands, for the reason that, being a gay and humorous fellow and a lover of good cheer, he harboured but few thoughts and would never work save when he could not help it; and so he used to say that doing nothing else but labour, without taking a little pleasure in the world, was no life for a Christian. He lived in close intimacy with Michelagnolo, for when that craftsman, supremely excellent beyond all who have ever lived, wished to have some recreation after his studies and his continuous labours of body and mind, no one was more pleasing to him for the purpose or more suited to his humour than this man. Jacopo worked for many years in Rome, or, to be more precise, he lived many years in Rome, working very little. By his hand, in that city, is the first chapel on the right hand as one enters the Church of S. Agostino by the door of the façade; on the vaulting of which chapel are the Apostles receiving the Holy Spirit, and on the wall below are two stories of Christ—in one His taking Peter and Andrew from their nets, and in the other the Feast of Simon and the Magdalene, in which there is a ceiling of planks and beams, counterfeited very well. In the panel of the same chapel, which he painted in oil, is a Dead Christ, wrought and executed with much mastery and diligence. In the Trinità at Rome, likewise, there is a little panel by his hand with the Coronation of Our  Lady.","label":[[0,23,"PER"],[47,71,"PER"],[91,95,"GPE"],[101,113,"PER"],[144,147,"PRON"],[166,168,"PRON"],[187,192,"PROD"],[209,211,"PRON"],[300,305,"PROD"],[318,321,"PRON"],[375,381,"PER"],[388,393,"PER"],[409,411,"PRON"],[455,459,"PRON"],[470,472,"PRON"],[488,490,"PRON"],[499,501,"PRON"],[615,624,"PER"],[615,624,"PER"],[626,628,"PRON"],[658,670,"PER"],[686,695,"PER"],[786,789,"PRON"],[802,805,"PRON"],[871,874,"PRON"],[909,912,"PRON"],[930,933,"PER"],[935,941,"PER"],[967,971,"GPE"],[997,999,"PRON"],[1020,1024,"GPE"],[1050,1053,"PRON"],[1068,1072,"GPE"],[1087,1093,"FAC"],[1130,1151,"FAC"],[1159,1163,"FAC"],[1171,1177,"FAC"],[1186,1194,"FAC"],[1204,1210,"FAC"],[1215,1253,"WORK"],[1219,1227,"MYTH"],[1219,1253,"MOTIF"],[1219,1253,"MYTH"],[1242,1253,"MYTH"],[1285,1292,"PROD"],[1296,1302,"MYTH"],[1310,1313,"PRON"],[1310,1353,"MOTIF"],[1310,1353,"WORK"],[1321,1326,"PER"],[1331,1337,"PER"],[1349,1353,"PROD"],[1372,1482,"WORK"],[1376,1408,"MYTH"],[1376,1457,"MOTIF"],[1385,1390,"MYTH"],[1399,1408,"MYTH"],[1430,1437,"FAC"],[1441,1447,"MAT"],[1452,1457,"MAT"],[1491,1496,"PROD"],[1509,1515,"FAC"],[1523,1525,"PRON"],[1537,1540,"MAT"],[1545,1612,"WORK"],[1547,1558,"MOTIF"],[1547,1558,"MYTH"],[1552,1558,"MYTH"],[1621,1636,"FAC"],[1632,1636,"GPE"],[1657,1716,"WORK"],[1675,1678,"PRON"],[1693,1716,"MYTH"],[1707,1716,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":701,"text":"And in the same city, on the first occasion when Duke Alessandro went there, he made a  most beautiful triumphal arch, with many figures in relief, at the gate of the Palazzo de' Signori; and also, in competition with other painters who executed a number of other works for the entry of the said Duke, the scenery for the representation of a play, which was held to be very beautiful.","label":[[16,20,"GPE"],[49,53,"PER"],[49,64,"PER"],[103,186,"WORK"],[113,117,"FAC"],[129,136,"PROD"],[140,146,"TECH"],[155,159,"FAC"],[167,186,"FAC"],[224,232,"PER"],[264,269,"PROD"],[296,300,"PER"],[306,313,"PROD"],[322,336,"PROD"],[342,346,"PROD"]]}
{"id":702,"text":"Afterwards, having gone to Rome at the time when the Emperor Charles V was expected there, he made some figures in clay, and a coat of arms in fresco for the Roman people on the Campidoglio, which was much extolled.","label":[[27,31,"GPE"],[32,89,"TIME"],[53,60,"PER"],[53,70,"PER"],[104,111,"PROD"],[115,119,"MAT"],[127,131,"PROD"],[135,139,"PROD"],[143,149,"TECH"],[158,170,"PER"],[178,189,"GPE"]]}
{"id":704,"text":"But the best work that ever issued from the hands of this master, and the most highly praised, was a little study wrought in stucco for the Duchess Margherita of Austria in the Palace of the Medici at Rome—a thing so beautiful and so ornate that there is nothing better to be seen; nor do I believe that it is possible, in a certain sense, to do with silver what L'Indaco did in this work with stucco.","label":[[13,17,"PROD"],[58,64,"PER"],[99,400,"WORK"],[108,113,"PROD"],[125,131,"TECH"],[140,147,"PER"],[140,169,"PER"],[162,169,"GPE"],[177,183,"FAC"],[177,205,"FAC"],[191,197,"ORG"],[201,205,"GPE"],[351,357,"MAT"],[363,371,"PER"],[384,388,"PROD"],[394,400,"TECH"]]}
