{"id":685,"text":"That very obligation which the craftsmen of painting owe to nature, who serves continually as model to those who are ever wresting the good from her best and most beautiful features and striving to counterfeit and to imitate her, should be owed, in my belief, to Giotto, painter of Florence, for the reason that, after the methods of good paintings and their outlines had lain buried for so many years under the ruins of the wars, he alone, although born among inept craftsmen, by the gift of God revived that art, which had come to a grievous pass, and brought it to such a form as could be called good. And truly it was a very great miracle that that age, gross and inept, should have had strength to work in Giotto in a fashion so masterly, that design, whereof the men of those times had little or no knowledge, was restored completely to life by means of him. And yet this great man was born at the village of Vespignano, in the district of Florence, fourteen miles distant from that city, in the year 1276, from a father named Bondone, a tiller of the soil and a simple fellow. He, having had this son, to whom he gave the name Giotto, reared him conformably to his condition; and when he had come to the age of ten, he showed in all his actions, although childish still, a vivacity and readiness of intelligence much out of the ordinary, which rendered him dear not only to his father but to all those also who knew him, both in the village and beyond. Now Bondone gave some sheep into his charge, and he, going about the holding, now in one part and now in another, to graze them, and impelled by a natural inclination to the art of design, was for ever drawing, on stones, on the ground, or on sand, something from nature, or in truth anything that came into his fancy. Wherefore Cimabue, going one day on some business of his own from Florence to Vespignano, found Giotto, while his sheep were browsing, portraying a sheep from nature on a flat and polished slab, with a stone slightly pointed, without having learnt any method of doing this from others, but only from nature; whence Cimabue, standing fast all in a marvel, asked him if he wished to go to live with him. The child answered that, his father consenting, he would go willingly.","label":[[31,40,"PER"],[44,52,"PROD"],[60,66,"LOC"],[94,99,"PROD"],[145,148,"PRON"],[225,228,"PRON"],[249,251,"PRON"],[263,290,"PER"],[271,278,"PER"],[282,290,"GPE"],[339,348,"PROD"],[353,358,"PRON"],[412,417,"LOC"],[425,429,"EVE"],[431,433,"PRON"],[467,476,"PER"],[493,496,"MYTH"],[510,513,"PER"],[562,564,"PRON"],[615,617,"PRON"],[635,642,"MYTH"],[711,717,"PER"],[749,755,"PROD"],[769,772,"PER"],[860,863,"PRON"],[884,887,"PER"],[904,911,"GPE"],[904,954,"GPE"],[934,954,"GPE"],[989,993,"GPE"],[995,1011,"TIME"],[1020,1026,"PER"],[1033,1082,"PER"],[1044,1050,"PER"],[1058,1062,"MAT"],[1076,1082,"PER"],[1084,1086,"PRON"],[1104,1107,"PER"],[1117,1119,"PRON"],[1134,1140,"PER"],[1149,1152,"PRON"],[1168,1171,"PRON"],[1192,1194,"PRON"],[1218,1221,"TIME"],[1223,1225,"PRON"],[1240,1243,"PRON"],[1360,1363,"PRON"],[1381,1384,"PRON"],[1385,1391,"PER"],[1423,1426,"PRON"],[1440,1447,"GPE"],[1464,1471,"PER"],[1482,1487,"ANIM"],[1493,1496,"PRON"],[1509,1511,"PRON"],[1583,1587,"PRON"],[1634,1637,"PROD"],[1641,1647,"PROD"],[1674,1680,"MAT"],[1689,1695,"MAT"],[1703,1707,"MAT"],[1724,1730,"LOC"],[1768,1771,"PRON"],[1789,1796,"PER"],[1820,1828,"PROD"],[1832,1835,"PRON"],[1845,1853,"GPE"],[1857,1867,"GPE"],[1875,1881,"PER"],[1889,1892,"PRON"],[1893,1898,"ANIM"],[1927,1932,"ANIM"],[1938,1944,"GPE"],[1968,1972,"PROD"],[1981,1986,"MAT"],[2079,2085,"GPE"],[2094,2101,"PER"],[2140,2143,"PRON"],[2147,2149,"PRON"],[2176,2179,"PRON"],[2185,2190,"PER"],[2206,2209,"PRON"],[2210,2216,"PER"],[2229,2231,"PRON"]]}
{"id":686,"text":"In the year 1322, likewise—Dante, very much his friend, having died in the year before, to his great sorrow—he went to Lucca, and at the request of Castruccio, then Lord of that city, his birthplace, he made a panel in S. Martino with a Christ in air and four Saints, Protectors of that city—namely, S. Peter, S. Regulus, S. Martin, and S. Paulinus—who appear to be recommending a Pope and an Emperor, who, according to what is believed by many, are Frederick of Bavaria and the Anti-Pope Nicholas V. Some, likewise, believe that Giotto designed the castle and fortress of Giusta, which is impregnable, at San Frediano, in the same city of Lucca.","label":[[0,16,"TIME"],[27,32,"PER"],[48,54,"PER"],[68,86,"TIME"],[119,124,"PER"],[148,158,"PER"],[165,169,"PER"],[178,182,"GPE"],[188,198,"GPE"],[208,499,"WORK"],[210,215,"PROD"],[219,229,"FAC"],[237,243,"MYTH"],[237,499,"MOTIF"],[260,266,"MYTH"],[268,278,"MYTH"],[300,308,"MYTH"],[310,320,"MYTH"],[322,331,"MYTH"],[337,348,"MYTH"],[381,385,"MYTH"],[393,400,"PER"],[450,470,"PER"],[463,470,"GPE"],[479,488,"MYTH"],[479,499,"MYTH"],[530,536,"PER"],[550,556,"FAC"],[550,645,"WORK"],[561,569,"FAC"],[573,579,"GPE"],[606,618,"GPE"],[632,636,"FAC"],[640,645,"GPE"]]}
{"id":687,"text":"This little panel, I say, having come into notice from the time when the book of these Lives was first published, was afterwards carried off by someone unknown, who, perhaps out of love for art and out of piety, it seeming to him that it was little esteemed, became, as said our poet, impious.","label":[[12,17,"PROD"],[50,112,"TIME"],[87,92,"PROD"],[190,193,"PROD"],[279,283,"PER"],[285,292,"PER"]]}
{"id":688,"text":"In the third, which is that of the Giugni, dedicated to the Apostles, there are painted by the hand of Giotto the stories of the martyrdom of many of them.","label":[[35,41,"PER"],[60,68,"PER"],[103,109,"PER"],[110,154,"WORK"],[114,121,"PROD"],[129,138,"MOTIF"],[129,138,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":689,"text":"In the fourth, which is on the other side of the church, towards the north, and belongs to the Tosinghi and to the Spinelli, and is dedicated to the Assumption of Our Lady, Giotto painted her Birth, her Marriage, her Annunciation, the Adoration of the Magi, and when she presents Christ as a little Child to Simeon, which is something very beautiful, seeing that, besides a great affection that is seen in that old man as he receives Christ, the action of the child, stretching out its arms in fear of him and turning in terror towards its mother, could not be more touching or more beautiful.","label":[[49,55,"FAC"],[95,103,"ORG"],[115,123,"ORG"],[149,171,"MYTH"],[163,171,"MYTH"],[173,179,"PER"],[192,197,"MOTIF"],[192,197,"MYTH"],[192,197,"WORK"],[203,211,"MOTIF"],[203,211,"MYTH"],[203,211,"WORK"],[217,229,"MOTIF"],[217,229,"MYTH"],[217,229,"WORK"],[231,256,"WORK"],[235,256,"MOTIF"],[235,256,"MYTH"],[252,256,"MYTH"],[262,592,"WORK"],[280,286,"MYTH"],[280,304,"MYTH"],[299,304,"PER"],[308,314,"MYTH"],[411,418,"PER"],[415,418,"PER"],[434,440,"MYTH"],[460,465,"PER"],[540,546,"PER"]]}
{"id":690,"text":"Giotto, having afterwards painted on a panel a large Crucifix coloured in distemper, for the Minerva, a church of the Preaching Friars, returned to his own country, having been abroad six years.","label":[[0,6,"PER"],[39,44,"PROD"],[45,134,"WORK"],[53,61,"MOTIF"],[53,61,"MYTH"],[74,83,"TECH"],[93,134,"FAC"],[104,110,"FAC"],[118,134,"MYTH"],[156,163,"GPE"],[184,193,"TIME"]]}
