{"id":705,"text":"Very great is the advantage bestowed by learning, without exception, on all those craftsmen who take delight in it, but particularly on sculptors, painters, and architects, for it opens up the way to invention in all the works that are made; not to mention that a man cannot have a perfect judgment, be his natural gifts what they may, if he is deprived of the complemental advantage of being assisted by learning. For who does not know that it is necessary, in choosing sites for buildings, to show enlightenment in the avoidance of danger from pestiferous winds, insalubrious air, and the smells and vapours of impure and unwholesome waters? Who is ignorant that a man must be able, in whatever work he is seeking to carry out, to reject or adopt everything for himself after mature consideration, without having to depend on help from another man's theory? For theory, when separated from practice, is generally of very little use; but when the two chance to come together, there is nothing that is more helpful to our life, both because art becomes much richer and more perfect by the aid of science, and because the counsels and the writings of learned craftsmen have in themselves greater efficacy and greater credit than the words or works of those who know nothing but mere practice, whether they do it well or ill. And that all this is true is seen manifestly in Leon Batista Alberti, who, having studied the Latin tongue, and having given attention to architecture, to perspective, and to painting, left behind him books written in such a manner, that, since not one of our modern craftsmen has been able to expound these matters in writing, although very many of them in his own country have excelled him in working, it is generally believed—such is the influence of his writings over the pens and speech of the learned—that he was superior to all those who were actually superior to him in work. Wherefore, with regard to name and fame, it is seen from experience that writings have greater power and longer life than anything else; for books go everywhere with ease, and everywhere they command belief, if only they be truthful and not full of lies. It is no marvel, then, if the famous Leon Batista is known more for his writings than for the work of his hands. This man, born in Florence of the most noble family of the Alberti, of which we have spoken in another place, devoted himself not only to studying geography and the proportions of antiquities, but also to writing, to which he was much inclined, much more than to working.","label":[[82,91,"PER"],[112,114,"PRON"],[136,145,"PER"],[147,155,"PER"],[161,171,"PER"],[177,179,"PRON"],[200,209,"PROD"],[221,226,"PROD"],[264,267,"PER"],[303,306,"PRON"],[339,341,"PRON"],[442,444,"PRON"],[471,476,"FAC"],[481,490,"FAC"],[667,670,"PER"],[697,701,"PROD"],[702,704,"PRON"],[764,771,"PRON"],[846,849,"PER"],[1018,1021,"PRON"],[1041,1044,"PROD"],[1096,1103,"PROD"],[1158,1167,"PER"],[1241,1246,"PROD"],[1300,1304,"PRON"],[1308,1310,"PRON"],[1372,1392,"PER"],[1418,1423,"PROD"],[1424,1430,"PROD"],[1462,1474,"PROD"],[1479,1490,"PROD"],[1499,1507,"PROD"],[1521,1524,"PRON"],[1525,1530,"PROD"],[1591,1600,"PER"],[1682,1685,"PRON"],[1690,1697,"GPE"],[1712,1715,"PRON"],[1728,1730,"PRON"],[1778,1781,"PRON"],[1800,1804,"PROD"],[1809,1815,"PROD"],[1836,1838,"PRON"],[1895,1898,"PRON"],[1902,1906,"PROD"],[1949,1951,"PRON"],[2049,2054,"PROD"],[2095,2099,"PRON"],[2163,2165,"PRON"],[2200,2212,"PER"],[2231,2234,"PRON"],[2265,2268,"PRON"],[2281,2284,"PER"],[2294,2302,"GPE"],[2315,2342,"ORG"],[2321,2327,"ORG"],[2353,2355,"PRON"],[2394,2401,"PRON"],[2423,2432,"PROD"],[2456,2467,"PROD"],[2481,2488,"PROD"],[2499,2501,"PRON"],[2539,2546,"PROD"]]}
{"id":706,"text":"He was excellent in arithmetic and geometry, and he wrote ten books on architecture in the Latin tongue, which were published by him in 1481, and may now be read in a translation in the Florentine tongue made by the Reverend Maestro Cosimo Bartoli, Provost of S. Giovanni in Florence.","label":[[20,30,"PROD"],[35,43,"PROD"],[62,67,"PROD"],[71,83,"PROD"],[91,103,"PROD"],[97,103,"PROD"],[136,140,"TIME"],[167,178,"PROD"],[186,203,"PROD"],[197,203,"PROD"],[216,224,"MYTH"],[216,283,"MYTH"],[225,232,"PER"],[249,256,"MYTH"],[260,271,"FAC"],[275,283,"GPE"]]}
{"id":707,"text":"Arriving at Rome in the time of Nicholas V, who had turned the whole of Rome upside down with his manner of building, Leon Batista, through the agency of Biondo da Forlì, who was much his friend, became intimate with that Pope, who had previously carried out all his building after the advice of Bernardo Rossellino, a sculptor and architect of Florence, as will be told in the Life of his brother Antonio.","label":[[12,16,"GPE"],[17,42,"TIME"],[32,42,"MYTH"],[72,76,"GPE"],[118,130,"PER"],[154,169,"PER"],[164,169,"GPE"],[222,226,"MYTH"],[267,275,"FAC"],[296,353,"PER"],[319,327,"PER"],[332,341,"PER"],[345,353,"GPE"],[378,382,"PROD"],[390,397,"PER"],[398,405,"PER"]]}
{"id":708,"text":"In the same chapel are the tombs of the said Signor Sigismondo and of his wife, constructed very richly of marble in the year 1450; on one there is the portrait of Sigismondo himself, and in another part of the work there is that of Leon Batista.","label":[[12,18,"FAC"],[45,62,"PER"],[74,78,"PER"],[107,113,"MAT"],[114,130,"TIME"],[148,174,"WORK"],[152,160,"PROD"],[152,174,"MOTIF"],[164,174,"PER"],[211,215,"PROD"],[233,245,"MOTIF"],[233,245,"PER"],[233,245,"WORK"]]}
{"id":709,"text":"Being then summoned by the same Marquis Lodovico to Mantua, Leon Batista made for him the models of the Church of S. Andrea and of some other works; and on the road leading from Mantua to Padua there may be seen certain temples built after his manner.","label":[[32,48,"PER"],[52,58,"GPE"],[60,72,"PER"],[90,96,"PROD"],[104,111,"FAC"],[104,123,"PER"],[114,123,"MYTH"],[142,147,"PROD"],[160,164,"GPE"],[178,184,"GPE"],[188,193,"GPE"],[220,227,"FAC"]]}
{"id":710,"text":"In Leon Batista's time Giovanni di Paolo Rucellai wished to build the principal façade of S. Maria Novella entirely of marble at his own expense, and he spoke of this to Leon Batista, who was very much his friend; and having received from him not only counsel, but the actual model, Giovanni resolved to have the work executed at all costs, in order to leave it behind him as a memorial of himself.","label":[[3,15,"PER"],[23,49,"PER"],[35,49,"PER"],[80,86,"FAC"],[90,98,"MYTH"],[90,106,"FAC"],[119,125,"MAT"],[170,182,"PER"],[206,212,"PER"],[276,281,"PROD"],[283,291,"PER"],[313,317,"PROD"],[378,386,"PROD"]]}
{"id":711,"text":"There is a work of Leon Batista's in a little Chapel of Our Lady on the abutment of the Ponte alla Carraja in Florence—namely, an altar-predella, containing three little scenes with some perspectives, which he was much more able to describe with the pen than to paint with the brush.","label":[[11,15,"PROD"],[19,31,"PER"],[39,64,"FAC"],[46,52,"FAC"],[56,64,"MYTH"],[72,80,"FAC"],[88,106,"FAC"],[110,118,"GPE"],[127,282,"WORK"],[130,144,"PROD"],[170,176,"PROD"],[187,199,"PROD"],[250,253,"PROD"],[277,282,"PROD"]]}
