{"id":678,"text":"If writers of history were to live a few years longer than the number commonly granted as the span of human life, I, for my part, have no manner of doubt that they would have something to add to the accounts of the past previously written by them, for the reason that, even as it is not possible for a single man, be he ever so diligent, to learn the exact truth in a flash, or to discover all the details of his subject in the little time at his command, so it is as clear as the light of day that Time, who is said to be the father of truth, is always revealing new things every day to the seeker after knowledge. If, many years ago, when I first wrote and also published these Lives of the Painters and other Craftsmen, I had possessed that full information which I have since received concerning Fra Giocondo of Verona, a man of rare parts and a master of all the most noble faculties, I would without a doubt have made that honourable record of him which I am now about to make for the benefit of craftsmen, or rather, of the world; and not of him only, but also of many other masters of Verona, who have been truly excellent. And let no one marvel that I place them all under the image of one only, because, not having been able to obtain portraits of them all, I am forced to do this; but, so far as in me lies, not one of them shall thereby have his excellence defrauded of its due. Now, since the order of time and merit so demands, I shall speak first of Fra Giocondo. This man, when he assumed the habit of S. Dominic, was called not simply Fra Giocondo, but Fra Giovanni Giocondo. How the name Giovanni dropped from him I know not, but I do know that he was always called Fra Giocondo by everyone. And although his  chief profession was that of letters, and he was not only a very good philosopher and theologian, but also an excellent Greek scholar (which was a rare thing at that time, when learning and letters were just beginning to revive in Italy), nevertheless he was also a very fine architect, being a man who always took supreme delight in that art, as Scaliger relates in his epistle against Cardan, and the learned Budé in his book \"De Asse,\" and in the observations that he wrote on the Pandects.","label":[[3,10,"PER"],[14,21,"PROD"],[114,115,"PRON"],[159,163,"PRON"],[242,246,"PRON"],[277,279,"PRON"],[309,312,"PER"],[317,319,"PRON"],[409,412,"PRON"],[409,412,"PRON"],[443,446,"PRON"],[459,461,"PRON"],[459,461,"PRON"],[499,503,"MYTH"],[527,533,"PER"],[641,642,"PRON"],[680,685,"PROD"],[693,701,"PER"],[712,721,"PER"],[723,724,"PRON"],[767,768,"PRON"],[800,822,"MYTH"],[816,822,"GPE"],[826,829,"PER"],[850,856,"PER"],[890,891,"PRON"],[940,946,"PROD"],[950,953,"PRON"],[960,961,"PRON"],[1002,1011,"PER"],[1031,1036,"LOC"],[1049,1052,"PRON"],[1082,1089,"PER"],[1093,1099,"GPE"],[1159,1160,"PRON"],[1167,1171,"PRON"],[1186,1191,"PROD"],[1245,1254,"PROD"],[1258,1262,"PRON"],[1268,1269,"PRON"],[1310,1312,"PRON"],[1330,1334,"PRON"],[1354,1357,"PRON"],[1382,1385,"PRON"],[1442,1443,"PRON"],[1465,1477,"MYTH"],[1484,1487,"PER"],[1494,1496,"PRON"],[1509,1514,"PROD"],[1518,1528,"MYTH"],[1552,1564,"MYTH"],[1570,1591,"MYTH"],[1606,1614,"PER"],[1628,1631,"PRON"],[1632,1633,"PRON"],[1648,1649,"PRON"],[1663,1665,"PRON"],[1684,1696,"MYTH"],[1723,1726,"PRON"],[1757,1764,"PROD"],[1770,1772,"PRON"],[1798,1809,"PER"],[1814,1824,"PER"],[1848,1853,"GPE"],[1854,1861,"PER"],[1905,1913,"PROD"],[1918,1925,"PROD"],[1959,1964,"GPE"],[1980,1982,"PRON"],[2004,2013,"PER"],[2023,2026,"PER"],[2067,2070,"PROD"],[2075,2083,"PER"],[2095,2098,"PRON"],[2099,2106,"PROD"],[2115,2121,"PER"],[2139,2143,"PER"],[2147,2150,"PRON"],[2151,2155,"PROD"],[2156,2166,"PROD"],[2196,2198,"PRON"],[2212,2220,"PROD"]]}
{"id":679,"text":"The same Giocondo wrote some observations, which are in print, on the Commentaries of Cæsar; and he was the first who made a drawing of the bridge built by Cæsar over the River Rhone, and described by him in those same Commentaries, but misunderstood in the time of Fra Giocondo.","label":[[9,17,"PER"],[70,82,"PROD"],[86,91,"PER"],[123,278,"WORK"],[125,132,"PROD"],[140,146,"FAC"],[156,161,"PER"],[171,176,"GPE"],[171,182,"GPE"],[219,231,"PROD"],[251,278,"TIME"],[266,269,"MYTH"],[266,278,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":680,"text":"Saying nothing of the learned, for with them I have nothing to do here, and continuing to speak of the men of our arts, who have always had an honourable abode in that most noble city, I come to Liberale of Verona, a disciple of Vincenzio di Stefano, a native of the same city, already mentioned in another place, who executed for the Church of Ognissanti, belonging to the Monks of S. Benedict, at Mantua, in the year 1463, a Madonna that was a very praiseworthy example of the work of those times.","label":[[103,106,"PER"],[114,118,"PROD"],[179,183,"GPE"],[195,276,"PER"],[207,213,"GPE"],[217,225,"PER"],[229,276,"PER"],[335,355,"FAC"],[345,355,"MYTH"],[374,379,"MYTH"],[374,394,"MYTH"],[383,394,"MYTH"],[399,405,"GPE"],[407,423,"TIME"],[425,498,"WORK"],[427,434,"MOTIF"],[427,434,"MYTH"],[479,483,"PROD"]]}
{"id":681,"text":"But no long time passed before he died, which was on the day of S. Chiara in the year 1536, at the age of eighty-five; and he was buried in S. Giovanni in Valle.","label":[[50,90,"TIME"],[64,73,"MYTH"],[140,151,"MYTH"],[140,160,"GPE"]]}
{"id":682,"text":"It is related by persons still living, who remember the facts very clearly, that at the time when Verona was under the power of that Emperor the bridge which is called the Ponte della Pietra, in that city, was being restored, and it was seen to be necessary to refound the central pier, which had been destroyed many times in the past, and Fra Giocondo gave the design for refounding it, and also for safeguarding it in such a manner that it might never be destroyed again.","label":[[17,24,"PER"],[98,104,"GPE"],[133,140,"PER"],[145,151,"FAC"],[172,190,"FAC"],[200,204,"GPE"],[281,285,"FAC"],[340,352,"MYTH"],[362,368,"PROD"]]}
{"id":683,"text":"When living in Paris in the service of King Louis XII, Fra Giocondo built two superb bridges over the Seine, covered with shops—works truly worthy of that magnanimous King and of the marvellous intellect of Fra Giocondo.","label":[[15,20,"GPE"],[39,43,"PER"],[39,53,"PER"],[55,67,"MYTH"],[74,219,"WORK"],[85,92,"FAC"],[102,107,"GPE"],[128,133,"PROD"],[167,171,"PER"],[207,219,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":684,"text":"The first paintings of Liberale were in the Chapel of the Monte della Pietà in S. Bernardino, in his native city; and there, in the principal picture, he painted a Deposition from the Cross, with certain Angels, some of whom have in their hands the Mysteries (for so they are called) of the Passion, and all with their weeping faces show grief at the Death of the Saviour.","label":[[10,19,"PROD"],[23,31,"PER"],[44,50,"FAC"],[44,92,"FAC"],[58,75,"MYTH"],[79,92,"FAC"],[108,112,"GPE"],[142,149,"PROD"],[162,371,"WORK"],[164,189,"MYTH"],[164,371,"MOTIF"],[184,189,"MYTH"],[204,210,"MYTH"],[249,298,"MYTH"],[291,298,"MYTH"],[351,371,"MYTH"],[364,371,"MYTH"]]}
