{"id":672,"text":"How many great and illustrious Princes, abounding with infinite wealth, would leave behind them a name renowned and glorious, if they possessed, together with their store of the goods of Fortune, a mind filled with grandeur and inclined to those things that not only embellish the world, but also confer vast benefit and advantage on the whole race of men! And what works can or should Princes and great persons undertake more readily than noble and magnificent buildings and edifices, both on account of the many kinds of men that are employed upon them in the making, and because, when made, they endure almost to eternity? For of all the costly enterprises that the ancient Romans executed at the time when they were at the supreme height of their greatness, what else is there left to us save those remains of buildings, the everlasting glory of the Roman name, which we revere as sacred things and strive to imitate as the sole patterns of the highest beauty? And how much these considerations occupied the minds of certain Princes who lived in the time of the Florentine architect, Antonio da San Gallo, will now be seen clearly in the Life of him that we are about to write. Antonio, then, was the son of Bartolommeo Picconi of Mugello, a maker of casks; and after having learned the joiner's craft in his boyhood, hearing that his uncle, Giuliano da San Gallo, was working at Rome in company with his brother Antonio, he set out from Florence for that city. And there, having devoted himself to the matters of the art of architecture with the greatest possible zeal, and pursuing that art, he gave promise of those achievements that we see in such abundance throughout all Italy, in the vast number of works executed by him at  a more mature age. Now it happened that Giuliano was forced by the torment that he suffered from the stone to return to Florence; and Antonio, having become known to the architect Bramante of Castel Durante, began to give assistance to that master, who, being old and crippled in the hands by palsy, was not able to work as before in the preparation of his designs.","label":[[31,38,"PER"],[91,95,"PRON"],[129,133,"PRON"],[159,164,"PRON"],[187,194,"MYTH"],[281,286,"GPE"],[352,355,"PER"],[366,371,"PROD"],[386,393,"PER"],[404,411,"PER"],[462,471,"FAC"],[476,484,"FAC"],[523,526,"PER"],[550,554,"PRON"],[594,598,"PRON"],[677,683,"PER"],[710,714,"PRON"],[745,750,"PRON"],[789,791,"PRON"],[814,823,"FAC"],[933,941,"PROD"],[1029,1036,"PER"],[1047,1108,"TIME"],[1066,1076,"PER"],[1066,1108,"PER"],[1077,1086,"PER"],[1142,1146,"PROD"],[1150,1153,"PRON"],[1182,1189,"PER"],[1205,1208,"PER"],[1212,1260,"PER"],[1235,1242,"GPE"],[1246,1251,"PER"],[1255,1260,"PROD"],[1291,1297,"PER"],[1300,1305,"PROD"],[1309,1312,"PRON"],[1335,1338,"PRON"],[1339,1344,"PER"],[1346,1367,"PER"],[1358,1367,"GPE"],[1384,1388,"GPE"],[1409,1416,"PER"],[1417,1424,"PER"],[1426,1428,"PRON"],[1442,1450,"PER"],[1460,1464,"GPE"],[1492,1499,"PRON"],[1522,1525,"PROD"],[1529,1541,"PROD"],[1593,1596,"PROD"],[1598,1600,"PRON"],[1681,1686,"GPE"],[1710,1715,"PROD"],[1728,1731,"PRON"],[1776,1784,"PER"],[1816,1818,"PRON"],[1837,1842,"MAT"],[1856,1864,"GPE"],[1870,1877,"PER"],[1906,1915,"PER"],[1906,1942,"PER"],[1928,1942,"GPE"],[1977,1983,"PER"],[2089,2092,"PRON"],[2093,2100,"PROD"]]}
{"id":673,"text":"In these he found himself served by Antonio with so much judgment, diligence, and expedition, that in the year 1512 he gave him the charge of the corridor that was to lead to the ditches of the Castello di S. Angelo; for which he began to receive a salary of ten crowns a month; but the death of Julius II then took place, and the work was left unfinished.","label":[[36,43,"PER"],[99,115,"TIME"],[146,154,"FAC"],[179,186,"FAC"],[194,215,"FAC"],[206,215,"MYTH"],[283,305,"TIME"],[296,305,"MYTH"],[331,335,"PROD"]]}
{"id":674,"text":"In the time of Pope Paul II, the Church of the Madonna of Loreto, which was small, and had its roof immediately over brick piers of rustic work, had been refounded and brought to that size in which it may be seen at the present day, by means of the skill and genius of Giuliano da Maiano; and it had been continued from the outer string-course upwards by Sixtus IV and by others, as has been related; but finally, in the time of Clement, in the year 1526, without having previously shown the slightest sign of falling, it cracked in such a manner, that not only the arches of the tribune were in danger, but the whole church in many places, for the reason that the foundations were weak and wanting in depth.","label":[[0,27,"TIME"],[15,19,"MYTH"],[15,27,"MYTH"],[33,39,"FAC"],[33,64,"FAC"],[47,54,"MYTH"],[58,64,"GPE"],[117,122,"MAT"],[123,128,"FAC"],[139,143,"PROD"],[213,231,"TIME"],[269,287,"PER"],[281,287,"GPE"],[355,364,"MYTH"],[414,454,"TIME"],[429,436,"MYTH"],[566,572,"FAC"],[580,587,"FAC"],[618,624,"FAC"],[665,676,"FAC"]]}
{"id":675,"text":"At this time a church dedicated to S. Maria di Loreto was being built at the Macello de' Corbi, near the Column of Trajan, in Rome, and it was brought to perfection by Antonio, with decorations of great beauty.","label":[[15,21,"FAC"],[15,53,"WORK"],[35,53,"MYTH"],[47,53,"GPE"],[77,94,"FAC"],[105,121,"FAC"],[126,130,"GPE"],[168,175,"PER"]]}
{"id":676,"text":"Afterwards, Pope Clement resolving, at the time when his nephew Alessandro de' Medici was Duke of Florence, to erect an impregnable fortress in that city, Signor Alessandro Vitelli, Pier Francesco da Viterbo, and Antonio laid out that castle, or rather, fortress, which is between the Porta al Prato and the Porta a S. Gallo, and caused it to be built with such rapidity, that no similar structure, whether ancient or modern, was ever completed so quickly.","label":[[12,16,"MYTH"],[12,24,"MYTH"],[36,106,"TIME"],[57,63,"PER"],[64,85,"PER"],[79,85,"ORG"],[90,94,"PER"],[90,106,"PER"],[98,106,"GPE"],[132,140,"FAC"],[149,153,"GPE"],[155,161,"PER"],[155,180,"PER"],[182,207,"PER"],[200,207,"GPE"],[213,220,"PER"],[235,241,"FAC"],[235,455,"WORK"],[254,262,"FAC"],[285,290,"FAC"],[285,299,"FAC"],[294,299,"GPE"],[308,313,"FAC"],[308,324,"FAC"],[316,324,"GPE"],[388,397,"FAC"]]}
{"id":677,"text":"After this, Cardinal Alborense, wishing to leave a memorial of himself in the church of his nation, caused a chapel of marble, with a tomb for himself, to be erected and brought to completion by Antonio in S. Jacopo degli Spagnuoli; which chapel, as has been related, was all painted in the spaces between the pilasters by Pellegrino da Modena, and on the altar stood a most beautiful S. James of marble executed by Jacopo Sansovino.","label":[[12,20,"MYTH"],[12,30,"MYTH"],[78,84,"FAC"],[107,432,"WORK"],[109,115,"FAC"],[119,125,"MAT"],[134,138,"FAC"],[134,138,"WORK"],[195,202,"PER"],[206,215,"MYTH"],[206,231,"FAC"],[239,245,"FAC"],[323,343,"PER"],[337,343,"GPE"],[356,361,"FAC"],[368,432,"WORK"],[385,393,"MOTIF"],[385,393,"MYTH"],[397,403,"MAT"],[416,432,"PER"]]}
