{"id":722,"text":"So potent are mastery and excellence, even when seen in only one or two works executed to perfection by a man in the art that he practises, that, no matter how small these may be, craftsmen and judges of art are forced to extol them, and writers are compelled to celebrate them and to give praise to the craftsman who has made them; even as we are now about to do for the Venetian Palma. This master, although not very eminent, nor remarkable for perfection of painting, was nevertheless so careful and diligent, and subjected himself so zealously to the labours of art, that a certain proportion of his works, if not all, have something good in them, in that they are close imitations of life and of the natural appearance of men. JACOPO PALMA (PALMA VECCHIO): S. BARBARA (Venice: S. Maria Formosa. Panel) View larger image Palma was much more remarkable for his patience in harmonizing and blending colours than for boldness of design, and he handled colour with extraordinary grace and finish. This may be seen in Venice from many pictures and portraits that he executed for various gentlemen; but of these I shall say nothing more, since I propose to content myself with making mention of some altar-pieces and of a head that I hold to be marvellous, or rather, divine. One of the altar-pieces he painted for S. Antonio, near Castello, at Venice, and another for S. Elena, near the Lido, where the Monks of Monte Oliveto have their monastery. In the latter, which is on the high-altar of that church, he painted the Magi presenting their offerings to Christ, with a good number of figures, among which are some heads truly worthy of praise, as also are the draperies,  executed with a beautiful flow of folds, which cover the figures.","label":[[72,77,"PROD"],[106,109,"PER"],[117,120,"PROD"],[126,128,"PRON"],[180,189,"PER"],[194,200,"PER"],[228,232,"PRON"],[273,277,"PRON"],[304,313,"PER"],[327,331,"PRON"],[341,343,"PRON"],[372,380,"PER"],[372,386,"PER"],[393,399,"PER"],[461,469,"PROD"],[527,534,"PRON"],[566,569,"PROD"],[600,603,"PRON"],[646,650,"PRON"],[660,664,"PRON"],[727,730,"PER"],[732,760,"PER"],[762,772,"MOTIF"],[762,772,"MYTH"],[762,772,"WORK"],[825,830,"PER"],[860,863,"PRON"],[930,936,"PROD"],[942,944,"PRON"],[1017,1023,"GPE"],[1034,1042,"PROD"],[1047,1056,"PROD"],[1062,1064,"PRON"],[1086,1095,"PER"],[1110,1111,"PER"],[1142,1143,"PRON"],[1163,1169,"PRON"],[1198,1210,"PROD"],[1220,1224,"PROD"],[1230,1231,"PRON"],[1274,1349,"WORK"],[1285,1297,"PROD"],[1313,1349,"FAC"],[1330,1338,"GPE"],[1343,1349,"GPE"],[1355,1390,"WORK"],[1367,1390,"FAC"],[1386,1390,"GPE"],[1402,1407,"MYTH"],[1402,1424,"MYTH"],[1411,1424,"GPE"],[1478,1488,"FAC"],[1497,1503,"FAC"],[1516,1737,"WORK"],[1520,1524,"MYTH"],[1520,1737,"MOTIF"],[1555,1561,"PER"],[1585,1592,"PROD"],[1615,1620,"PROD"],[1661,1670,"PROD"],[1730,1737,"PROD"]]}
{"id":723,"text":"For so much did the genius of Palma effect in this particular work, that he made it quite miraculous and beautiful beyond belief, as all men declare, the picture being seen almost every year at the Festival of the Ascension.","label":[[30,35,"PER"],[62,66,"PROD"],[154,161,"PROD"],[191,223,"TIME"]]}
{"id":724,"text":"There, opposite to that work, in the year 1548, Giorgio Vasari executed for Don Romualdo da Verona, Abbot of that place, another panel-picture containing the Deposition of Christ from the Cross, with a large number of figures.","label":[[24,28,"PROD"],[30,46,"TIME"],[48,62,"PER"],[76,119,"MYTH"],[92,98,"GPE"],[100,105,"MYTH"],[129,142,"PER"],[129,225,"WORK"],[158,193,"MYTH"],[158,225,"MOTIF"],[172,178,"MYTH"],[188,193,"MYTH"],[218,225,"PROD"]]}
{"id":725,"text":"After these works Lorenzo went to Ancona, at the very time when Mariano da Perugia had finished a panel-picture, with a large ornamental frame, for the high-altar of S. Agostino.","label":[[12,17,"PROD"],[18,25,"PER"],[34,40,"GPE"],[42,177,"TIME"],[64,82,"PER"],[96,177,"WORK"],[98,111,"PROD"],[126,142,"PROD"],[137,142,"PROD"],[152,162,"FAC"],[166,177,"FAC"]]}
{"id":726,"text":"Palma also painted a lifesize S. Barbara for the altar of the Bombardieri in the Church of S. Maria Formosa, with two smaller figures at the sides, S. Sebastian and S. Anthony; and the S. Barbara is one of the best figures that this painter ever executed.","label":[[0,5,"PER"],[19,254,"WORK"],[30,40,"MOTIF"],[30,40,"MYTH"],[49,54,"FAC"],[62,73,"PER"],[81,87,"FAC"],[81,107,"FAC"],[91,107,"MYTH"],[109,175,"MOTIF"],[126,133,"PROD"],[148,160,"MYTH"],[165,175,"MYTH"],[185,195,"MYTH"],[215,222,"PROD"],[233,240,"PER"]]}
{"id":727,"text":"This did not give much satisfaction; and Lorenzo was commissioned to paint a picture, which is placed in the middle of the same church, of Our Lady with the Child in her lap, and two figures of Angels in the air, in foreshortening, crowning the Virgin.","label":[[41,48,"PER"],[75,251,"WORK"],[77,84,"PROD"],[128,134,"FAC"],[139,162,"MYTH"],[139,251,"MOTIF"],[183,190,"PROD"],[194,200,"MYTH"],[245,251,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":728,"text":"This Rondinello, after leaving Giovanni Bellini, laboured at his art to such purpose, that, being very diligent, he executed many works worthy of praise; of which we have witness in the panel-picture of the high-altar in the Duomo at Forlì, showing Christ giving the Communion to the Apostles, which he painted there with his own hand, executing it very well.","label":[[5,15,"PER"],[31,47,"PER"],[65,68,"PROD"],[130,135,"PROD"],[182,358,"WORK"],[186,199,"PROD"],[207,217,"FAC"],[225,239,"FAC"],[234,239,"GPE"],[249,255,"MYTH"],[249,292,"MOTIF"],[267,276,"MYTH"],[284,292,"MYTH"]]}
