{"id":620,"text":"Andrea del Verrocchio, a Florentine, was in his day a goldsmith, a master of perspective, a sculptor, a wood-carver, a painter, and a musician; but in the arts of sculpture and painting, to tell the truth, he had a manner somewhat hard and crude, as one who acquired it rather by infinite study than by the facility of a natural gift. Even if he had been as poor in this facility as he was rich in the study and diligence that exalted him, he would have been most excellent in those arts, which, for their highest perfection, require a union of study and natural power. If either of these is wanting, a man rarely attains to the first rank; but study will do a great deal, and thus Andrea, who had it in greater abundance than any other craftsman whatsoever, is counted among the rare and excellent masters of our arts. In his youth he applied himself to the sciences, particularly to geometry. Among many other things that he made while working at the goldsmith's art were certain buttons for copes, which are in S. Maria del Fiore at Florence; and he also made larger works, particularly a cup, full of animals, foliage, and other bizarre fancies, which is known to all goldsmiths, and casts are taken of it; and likewise another, on which there is a very beautiful dance of little children. Having given a proof of his powers in these two works, he was commissioned by the Guild of Merchants to make two scenes in silver for the ends of the altar of S. Giovanni, from which, when put into execution, he acquired very great praise and fame. There were wanting at this time in Rome some of those large figures of the Apostles which generally stood on the altar of the Chapel of the Pope, as well as certain other works in silver that had been destroyed; wherefore Pope Sixtus sent for Andrea and with great favour commissioned him to do all that was necessary in this matter, and he brought the whole to perfection with much diligence and judgment.","label":[[0,35,"PER"],[25,35,"PER"],[44,47,"PRON"],[54,63,"PER"],[67,73,"PER"],[77,88,"TECH"],[92,100,"PER"],[104,115,"PER"],[119,126,"PER"],[134,142,"PER"],[155,159,"PROD"],[163,172,"PROD"],[177,185,"PROD"],[206,208,"PRON"],[267,269,"PRON"],[343,345,"PRON"],[383,385,"PRON"],[435,438,"PRON"],[440,442,"PRON"],[483,487,"PROD"],[603,606,"PER"],[682,688,"PER"],[698,700,"PRON"],[737,746,"PER"],[799,806,"PER"],[814,818,"PROD"],[823,826,"PRON"],[844,851,"PRON"],[859,867,"PROD"],[885,893,"PROD"],[924,926,"PRON"],[953,962,"PER"],[965,968,"PROD"],[982,989,"PROD"],[994,999,"PROD"],[1014,1022,"MYTH"],[1014,1044,"FAC"],[1036,1044,"GPE"],[1050,1052,"PRON"],[1070,1075,"PROD"],[1090,1209,"WORK"],[1092,1095,"PROD"],[1105,1112,"ANIM"],[1105,1148,"MOTIF"],[1114,1121,"PLANT"],[1172,1182,"PER"],[1188,1193,"PROD"],[1207,1209,"PRON"],[1268,1273,"PROD"],[1268,1292,"MOTIF"],[1268,1292,"WORK"],[1284,1292,"PER"],[1318,1321,"PRON"],[1342,1347,"PROD"],[1349,1351,"PRON"],[1376,1381,"ORG"],[1376,1394,"ORG"],[1385,1394,"PER"],[1403,1541,"WORK"],[1407,1413,"PROD"],[1407,1413,"PROD"],[1417,1423,"MAT"],[1417,1423,"MAT"],[1444,1449,"FAC"],[1453,1464,"FAC"],[1503,1505,"PRON"],[1562,1574,"TIME"],[1578,1582,"GPE"],[1618,1626,"MYTH"],[1656,1661,"FAC"],[1669,1675,"FAC"],[1669,1687,"FAC"],[1683,1687,"MYTH"],[1714,1719,"PROD"],[1723,1729,"MAT"],[1765,1769,"MYTH"],[1765,1776,"MYTH"],[1786,1792,"PER"],[1828,1831,"PRON"],[1881,1883,"PRON"]]}
{"id":621,"text":"He also made for Lorenzo de' Medici, for the fountain of his Villa at Careggi, a boy of bronze squeezing a fish, which the Lord Duke Cosimo has caused to be placed, as may be seen at the present day, on the fountain that is in the courtyard of his Palace; which boy is truly marvellous.","label":[[17,35,"PER"],[29,35,"ORG"],[61,77,"FAC"],[70,77,"GPE"],[79,285,"WORK"],[81,84,"PER"],[81,111,"MOTIF"],[88,94,"MAT"],[107,111,"ANIM"],[123,127,"PER"],[123,139,"PER"],[128,132,"PER"],[180,198,"TIME"],[207,215,"FAC"],[231,240,"FAC"],[248,254,"FAC"],[262,265,"PER"]]}
{"id":622,"text":"Now the due occasion arrived in the form of the death of Giuliano de' Medici and the danger incurred by his brother Lorenzo, who was wounded in S. Maria del Fiore, when it was ordained by the friends and relatives of Lorenzo that images of him should be set up in many places, to render thanks to God for his deliverance.","label":[[44,76,"TIME"],[57,76,"PER"],[70,76,"ORG"],[108,115,"PER"],[116,123,"PER"],[144,152,"MYTH"],[144,162,"FAC"],[192,199,"PER"],[204,213,"PER"],[217,224,"PER"],[297,300,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":623,"text":"There lived in the time of Andrea one Benedetto Buglioni, who received the secret of glazed terra-cotta work from a woman related to the house of Andrea della Robbia; wherefore he made many works in that manner both in Florence and abroad, particularly a Christ rising from the dead, with certain angels, which, for a work in glazed terra-cotta, is beautiful enough, in the Church of the Servi, near the Chapel of S. Barbara.","label":[[12,33,"TIME"],[27,33,"PER"],[38,56,"PER"],[92,103,"MAT"],[104,108,"PROD"],[116,121,"PER"],[137,142,"FAC"],[146,165,"PER"],[190,195,"PROD"],[219,227,"PER"],[253,424,"WORK"],[255,261,"PER"],[255,303,"MOTIF"],[278,282,"MYTH"],[297,303,"MYTH"],[318,322,"PROD"],[333,344,"MAT"],[374,380,"FAC"],[374,424,"FAC"],[388,393,"MYTH"],[404,424,"FAC"]]}
{"id":625,"text":"Wherefore, although he did not put the aforesaid cartoons into execution, yet he did paint certain pictures; among others, a panel for the Nuns of S. Domenico in Florence, wherein it appeared to him that he had acquitted himself very well; whence, no long time after, he painted another in S. Salvi for the Monks of Vallombrosa, containing the Baptism of Christ by S. John. In this work he was assisted by Leonardo da Vinci, his disciple, then quite young, who painted therein an angel with his own hand, which was much better than the other parts of the work; and for that reason Andrea resolved never again to touch a brush, since Leonardo, young as he was, had acquitted himself in that art much better than he had done.","label":[[49,57,"PROD"],[99,107,"PROD"],[123,238,"WORK"],[125,130,"PROD"],[139,143,"ORG"],[139,170,"ORG"],[147,158,"FAC"],[162,170,"GPE"],[290,298,"FAC"],[307,312,"MYTH"],[307,327,"MYTH"],[316,327,"GPE"],[340,722,"WORK"],[344,372,"MOTIF"],[344,372,"MYTH"],[355,361,"MYTH"],[365,372,"MYTH"],[382,386,"PROD"],[406,423,"PER"],[418,423,"GPE"],[429,437,"PER"],[480,485,"MYTH"],[555,559,"PROD"],[581,587,"PER"],[620,625,"PROD"],[633,641,"PER"],[690,693,"PROD"]]}
{"id":626,"text":"The Venetians, meanwhile, wishing to honour the great valour of Bartolommeo da Bergamo, thanks to whom they had gained many victories, in order to encourage others, and having heard the fame of Andrea, summoned him to Venice, where he was commissioned to make an equestrian statue of that captain in bronze, to be placed on the Piazza di SS.","label":[[4,13,"PER"],[64,86,"PER"],[79,86,"GPE"],[124,133,"EVE"],[194,200,"PER"],[218,224,"GPE"],[260,340,"WORK"],[263,280,"PROD"],[274,280,"PROD"],[289,296,"PER"],[300,306,"MAT"],[328,340,"FAC"]]}
