{"id":729,"text":"Parri di Spinello Spinelli, painter of Arezzo, having learnt the first principles of art from his own father, was brought to Florence by the agency of Messer Leonardo Bruni of Arezzo, and was received by Lorenzo Ghiberti into his school, where many young men were learning under his discipline: and since the doors of S. Giovanni were then being given their finish, he was put to labour on those figures, in company with many others, as it has been said above. And having, in this work, contracted a friendship with Masolino da Panicale, and being pleased with his method of drawing, he set about imitating him in many respects, as he also imitated in others the manner of Don Lorenzo degli Angeli. Parri made his figures much longer and more slender than any painter who had lived before him, and whereas the others make them in the proportion of ten heads at most, he gave them eleven, and sometimes twelve; nor did this make them awkward, although they were slender and were ever bent in an arch either to the right side or to the left, for the reason that this, as it appeared to him, and as he himself said, gave them more vigour. The flow of his draperies was very delicate, with abundance of folds, which fell from the arms of his figures right down to the feet. He coloured very well in distemper, and perfectly in fresco, and he was the first who, in working in fresco, ceased to use verdaccio below flesh-colours, to be afterwards washed over with rosy flesh-tints in chiaroscuro, in the manner of water-colours, as Giotto and the other old masters had done. Parri, on the other hand, used body colours in making his grounds and tints, placing them with much discretion where it appeared to him that they would look best—that is, the lights on the highest points, the middle tints towards the sides, and the darks on the outlines; with which method of painting he showed more facility in his works and gave longer life to pictures in fresco, seeing that, having laid the colours in their places, he would blend them together with a rather thick and soft brush, and would execute his works with so high a finish that nothing better can be desired; and his colouring has no equal. Parri, then, having been absent many years from his country, was recalled by his relatives, after the death of his father, to Arezzo, where, besides many works which it would take too long to recount, he made some which do not in any way deserve to be passed over in silence.","label":[[0,45,"PER"],[9,26,"PER"],[28,35,"PER"],[39,45,"GPE"],[85,88,"PROD"],[94,97,"PRON"],[102,108,"PER"],[125,133,"GPE"],[151,157,"PER"],[151,182,"PER"],[176,182,"GPE"],[204,220,"PER"],[226,229,"PRON"],[230,236,"FAC"],[249,258,"PER"],[255,258,"PER"],[279,282,"PRON"],[283,293,"PROD"],[309,314,"FAC"],[318,329,"FAC"],[352,357,"PRON"],[366,368,"PRON"],[396,403,"PROD"],[437,439,"PRON"],[481,485,"PROD"],[516,536,"PER"],[528,536,"GPE"],[561,564,"PRON"],[561,564,"PRON"],[575,582,"PROD"],[584,586,"PRON"],[607,610,"WORK"],[632,634,"PRON"],[673,696,"MYTH"],[699,704,"PER"],[710,713,"PRON"],[714,721,"PROD"],[760,767,"PER"],[789,792,"PRON"],[822,826,"PRON"],[867,869,"PRON"],[875,879,"PRON"],[928,932,"PRON"],[951,955,"PRON"],[1069,1071,"PRON"],[1084,1087,"PRON"],[1096,1098,"PRON"],[1148,1151,"PRON"],[1152,1161,"PROD"],[1234,1237,"PRON"],[1238,1245,"PROD"],[1270,1272,"PRON"],[1295,1304,"TECH"],[1323,1329,"TECH"],[1371,1377,"TECH"],[1478,1489,"TECH"],[1526,1532,"PER"],[1547,1558,"PER"],[1569,1574,"PER"],[1623,1626,"PRON"],[1654,1658,"PRON"],[1686,1688,"PRON"],[1701,1704,"PRON"],[1710,1714,"PRON"],[1862,1870,"PROD"],[1871,1873,"PRON"],[1898,1901,"PRON"],[1902,1907,"PROD"],[1932,1940,"PROD"],[1944,1950,"TECH"],[2006,2008,"PRON"],[2064,2069,"PROD"],[2089,2092,"PRON"],[2093,2098,"PROD"],[2161,2164,"PRON"],[2189,2194,"PER"],[2237,2240,"PRON"],[2241,2248,"GPE"],[2266,2269,"PRON"],[2270,2279,"PER"],[2281,2310,"TIME"],[2304,2310,"PER"],[2315,2321,"GPE"],[2343,2348,"PROD"],[2355,2357,"PRON"],[2390,2392,"PRON"]]}
{"id":730,"text":"In the old Audience Chamber of the Fraternity of S. Maria della Misericordia, Parri painted a Madonna who has under her mantle the people of Arezzo, wherein he portrayed from the life those who then ruled that holy place, clothed according to the use of those times; and among them one called Braccio, who is now called, when there is talk of him, Lazzaro Ricco, and who died in the year 1422, leaving all his riches and means to that place, which dispenses them in the service of God's poor, performing the holy works of mercy with much charity.","label":[[11,27,"FAC"],[11,76,"FAC"],[35,45,"MYTH"],[49,76,"FAC"],[78,83,"PER"],[92,545,"WORK"],[94,101,"MYTH"],[94,147,"MOTIF"],[120,126,"PROD"],[131,147,"PER"],[141,147,"GPE"],[184,300,"MOTIF"],[210,220,"MYTH"],[293,300,"PER"],[348,361,"PER"],[376,392,"TIME"],[481,484,"MYTH"],[481,491,"MYTH"],[487,491,"PER"],[513,518,"PROD"],[522,527,"MYTH"],[538,545,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":731,"text":"This panel is brought out every year on the second day of June, and, after it has been borne in solemn procession by the men of the said Company as far as the church of the said Saints, there is placed over it a coffer of silver, wrought by the goldsmith Forzore, brother of Parri, within which are the bodies of the said SS.","label":[[5,10,"PROD"],[37,62,"TIME"],[121,124,"PER"],[137,144,"ORG"],[159,165,"FAC"],[178,184,"MYTH"],[212,218,"FAC"],[222,228,"MAT"],[245,254,"PER"],[245,280,"PER"],[264,271,"PER"],[275,280,"PER"],[322,324,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":732,"text":"But returning to Parri: after the said work, he painted in fresco in a chapel of the Church and Hospital of S. Cristofano, beside the Company of the Nunziata, for Mona Mattea de' Testi, wife of Carcascion Florinaldi, who left a very good endowment to that little church; and there he made Christ Crucified, with many angels round Him and above Him, flying in a certain dark sky and weeping bitterly.","label":[[17,22,"PER"],[39,43,"PROD"],[59,65,"TECH"],[71,77,"FAC"],[85,91,"FAC"],[85,157,"FAC"],[96,104,"FAC"],[108,121,"MYTH"],[134,157,"FAC"],[163,167,"MYTH"],[163,215,"MYTH"],[186,190,"PER"],[194,215,"PER"],[263,269,"FAC"],[289,295,"MYTH"],[289,305,"MYTH"],[289,398,"MOTIF"],[289,398,"WORK"],[317,323,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":733,"text":"It is said that while Parri was executing this work, Fra Bernardino da Siena, a friar of S. Francis and a man of holy life, was preaching in Arezzo, and that having brought many of his brother monks into the true religious life, and having converted many other persons, he caused Parri to make the model for the Church of Sargiano, which he was building for them; and that afterwards, having heard that many evil things were going on in a wood near a fountain, a mile distant from the city, he went there one morning, followed by the whole people of Arezzo, with a great wooden cross in his hand, such as he was wont to carry, and after preaching a solemn sermon he had the fountain destroyed and the wood cut down; and a little later he caused a beginning to be made with a little chapel which was built there in honour of Our Lady, with the title of S. Maria delle Grazie, wherein he afterwards asked Parri to paint with his own hand, as he did, the Virgin in Glory, who, opening her arms, is covering under her mantle the whole people of Arezzo.","label":[[22,27,"PER"],[47,51,"PROD"],[53,122,"MYTH"],[71,76,"GPE"],[80,85,"MYTH"],[89,99,"MYTH"],[106,109,"PER"],[113,122,"MYTH"],[141,147,"GPE"],[185,198,"MYTH"],[213,227,"MYTH"],[261,268,"PER"],[280,285,"PER"],[298,303,"PROD"],[312,330,"FAC"],[439,443,"GPE"],[451,459,"FAC"],[485,489,"GPE"],[540,546,"PER"],[550,556,"GPE"],[578,583,"MYTH"],[656,662,"MYTH"],[701,705,"MAT"],[782,788,"FAC"],[824,832,"MYTH"],[852,873,"FAC"],[903,908,"PER"],[949,1047,"WORK"],[952,958,"MYTH"],[952,967,"MYTH"],[952,1047,"MOTIF"],[1014,1020,"PROD"],[1031,1037,"PER"],[1041,1047,"GPE"]]}
