{"id":748,"text":"Michele San Michele, who was born at Verona in the year 1484, and learned the first principles of architecture from his father Giovanni and his uncle Bartolommeo, both excellent architects, went off at sixteen years of age to Rome, leaving his father and two brothers of fine parts, one of whom, called Jacopo, devoted himself to letters, and the other, named Don Camillo, was a Canon Regular and General of that Order. Having arrived there, he studied the ancient remains of architecture in such a manner, and with such diligence, observing and measuring everything minutely, that in a short time he became renowned and famous not only in Rome, but throughout all the places that are around that city. Moved by his fame, the people of Orvieto summoned him as architect to their celebrated temple, with an honourable salary; and while he was employed in their service, he was summoned for the same reason to Monte Fiascone, as architect for the building of their principal temple; and thus, serving both the one and the other of these places, he executed all that there is to be seen in these two cities in the way of good architecture. Among other works, a most beautiful tomb was built after his design in S. Domenico at Monte Fiascone—I believe, for one of the Petrucci, a nobleman of Siena—which cost a great sum of money, and proved to be marvellous. Besides all this, he made an infinite number of designs for private houses in those places, and made himself known as a man of great judgment and excellence. Thereupon Pope Clement VII, proposing to make use of him in the most important operations of the wars that were stirring at that time throughout all Italy, gave him as a companion to Antonio da San Gallo,  with a very good salary, to the end that they might go together to inspect all the places of greatest importance in the States of the Church, and, wherever necessary, might see to the construction of fortifications; above all, at Parma and Piacenza, because those two cities were most distant from Rome, and nearest and most exposed to the perils of war. Which duty having been executed by Michele and Antonio to the full satisfaction of the Pontiff, there came to Michele a desire, after all those years, to revisit his native city and his relatives and friends, and even more to see the fortresses of the Venetians.","label":[[0,19,"PER"],[37,43,"GPE"],[47,60,"TIME"],[98,110,"PROD"],[116,119,"PRON"],[120,126,"PER"],[127,135,"PER"],[140,143,"PRON"],[144,149,"PER"],[150,161,"PER"],[178,188,"PER"],[202,215,"TIME"],[226,230,"GPE"],[240,243,"PRON"],[244,250,"PER"],[259,267,"PER"],[303,309,"PER"],[319,326,"PRON"],[330,337,"PROD"],[360,371,"MYTH"],[379,392,"MYTH"],[397,404,"MYTH"],[413,418,"MYTH"],[442,444,"PRON"],[476,488,"PROD"],[598,600,"PRON"],[640,644,"GPE"],[669,675,"GPE"],[697,701,"GPE"],[712,715,"PRON"],[726,732,"PER"],[736,743,"GPE"],[753,756,"PRON"],[760,769,"PER"],[790,796,"FAC"],[835,837,"PRON"],[854,859,"PRON"],[869,871,"PRON"],[908,922,"GPE"],[927,936,"PER"],[945,953,"FAC"],[973,979,"FAC"],[1043,1045,"PRON"],[1097,1103,"GPE"],[1123,1135,"PROD"],[1149,1154,"PROD"],[1173,1177,"FAC"],[1198,1204,"PROD"],[1208,1219,"MYTH"],[1208,1237,"FAC"],[1223,1237,"GPE"],[1238,1239,"PRON"],[1253,1293,"PER"],[1264,1272,"ORG"],[1276,1284,"PER"],[1288,1293,"GPE"],[1374,1376,"PRON"],[1404,1411,"PROD"],[1424,1430,"FAC"],[1457,1464,"PRON"],[1476,1479,"PER"],[1524,1528,"MYTH"],[1524,1540,"MYTH"],[1567,1570,"PRON"],[1611,1615,"EVE"],[1663,1668,"GPE"],[1675,1678,"PRON"],[1697,1717,"PER"],[1708,1717,"GPE"],[1840,1846,"GPE"],[1840,1860,"GPE"],[1854,1860,"MYTH"],[1920,1934,"FAC"],[1950,1955,"GPE"],[1960,1968,"GPE"],[1988,1994,"GPE"],[2018,2022,"GPE"],[2070,2073,"EVE"],[2110,2117,"PER"],[2122,2129,"PER"],[2162,2169,"MYTH"],[2185,2192,"PER"],[2237,2240,"PRON"],[2248,2252,"GPE"],[2257,2260,"PRON"],[2261,2270,"PER"],[2275,2282,"PER"],[2309,2319,"FAC"],[2327,2336,"PER"]]}
{"id":749,"text":"Michele died in the year 1559, and was buried in S. Tommaso, a church of Carmelite Friars, where there is the ancient burial-place of his forefathers; and at the present day Messer Niccolò San Michele, a physician, has set his hand to erecting him an honourable tomb, which is even now being carried into execution.","label":[[0,7,"PER"],[13,29,"TIME"],[49,59,"MYTH"],[49,89,"FAC"],[63,69,"FAC"],[73,89,"MYTH"],[118,130,"FAC"],[138,149,"PER"],[174,213,"PER"],[204,213,"PER"],[262,266,"PROD"]]}
{"id":750,"text":"In the house of Messer Pellegrino Ridolfi, also at Verona, the same master painted the Coronation of the Emperor Charles V, and the scene when, after being crowned in Bologna, he rides with the Pope through the city in great pomp.","label":[[7,12,"FAC"],[16,22,"PER"],[16,41,"PER"],[51,57,"GPE"],[83,122,"WORK"],[87,97,"EVE"],[87,122,"EVE"],[87,122,"MOTIF"],[105,122,"PER"],[128,229,"WORK"],[132,137,"PROD"],[144,229,"MOTIF"],[167,174,"GPE"],[194,198,"MYTH"],[211,215,"GPE"]]}
{"id":751,"text":"Monsignor Luigi Lippomani, Bishop of Verona, having resolved to carry to completion the campanile of his church, which had been begun a hundred years before, caused a design for this to be made by Michele, who did it very beautifully, taking into consideration the preserving of the old part and the expense that the Bishop was able to incur.","label":[[0,9,"MYTH"],[0,43,"MYTH"],[27,33,"MYTH"],[37,43,"GPE"],[88,97,"FAC"],[101,104,"PRON"],[105,111,"FAC"],[167,173,"PROD"],[197,204,"PER"],[317,323,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":752,"text":"It was then resolved at Verona to rebuild the Lazzaretto, a dwelling, or rather, hospital, which serves for the sick in times of plague, the old one having been destroyed together with other edifices that had been in the suburbs; and Michele was commissioned to make a design for this (which proved to be beautiful beyond all expectations), to the end that it might be put into execution on a spot near the river, at some distance from the city and beyond the esplanade.","label":[[24,30,"GPE"],[42,135,"WORK"],[46,89,"FAC"],[60,68,"FAC"],[81,89,"FAC"],[191,199,"FAC"],[221,228,"GPE"],[234,241,"PER"],[269,275,"PROD"],[407,412,"GPE"],[440,444,"GPE"],[460,469,"GPE"]]}
{"id":753,"text":"In Venice he built from the foundations the very rich and magnificent palace of the Cornaro family, near S. Polo, and restored another palace, also of the Cornaro family, which is by S. Benedetto all'Albore, for M. Giovanni Cornaro, of whom Michele was much the friend; and this led to Giorgio Vasari painting nine pictures in oils for the ceiling of a magnificent apartment, all adorned with woodwork carved and richly  overlaid with gold, in that palace.","label":[[3,9,"GPE"],[28,39,"FAC"],[40,112,"WORK"],[70,76,"FAC"],[84,98,"ORG"],[105,112,"FAC"],[135,141,"FAC"],[135,268,"WORK"],[155,169,"ORG"],[183,206,"PER"],[212,231,"PER"],[241,248,"PER"],[262,268,"PER"],[286,300,"PER"],[310,455,"WORK"],[315,323,"PROD"],[327,331,"TECH"],[340,347,"FAC"],[365,374,"FAC"],[393,401,"MAT"],[435,439,"MAT"],[449,455,"FAC"]]}
