{"id":718,"text":"Nanni d'Antonio di Banco was not only rich enough by patrimony, but also by no means humble in origin, yet, delighting in sculpture, he was not only not ashamed to learn and practise it, but took no small pride therein, and made so much advance that his fame will ever endure; and it will be all the more celebrated in proportion as men know that he applied himself to this noble art not through necessity, but through a true love of the art itself. This man, who was one of the disciples of Donato, although I have placed him before his master because he died long before him, was a somewhat sluggish person, but modest, humble, and kindly in his dealings. There is by his hand, in Florence, the S. Philip of marble which is on a pilaster on the outside of the Oratory of Orsanmichele. This work was at first allotted to Donato by the Guild of Shoemakers, and then, since they could not agree with him about the price, it was transferred, as though in despite of Donato, to Nanni, who promised that he would take whatsoever payment they might give him, and would ask no other. But the business fell out otherwise, for, when the statue was finished and set in its place, he asked a much greater price for his work than Donato had done at the beginning; wherefore the valuation of it was referred by both parties to Donato, the Consuls of that Guild believing firmly that he, out of envy at not having made it, would value it at much less than if it were his own work; but they were disappointed in their belief, for Donato judged that much more should be paid to Nanni for his statue than he had demanded. Being in no way willing to abide by this judgment, the Consuls made an outcry and said to Donato: \"Why dost thou, after undertaking to make this work at a smaller price, value it higher when made by the hand of another, and constrain us to give him more for it than he himself demands? For thou knowest, even as we do also, that from thy hands it would have come out much better.\"","label":[[0,24,"PER"],[8,24,"PER"],[122,131,"PROD"],[133,135,"PRON"],[183,185,"PRON"],[250,253,"PRON"],[281,283,"PRON"],[333,336,"PER"],[347,349,"PRON"],[358,365,"PRON"],[380,383,"PROD"],[438,441,"PROD"],[455,458,"PER"],[479,488,"PER"],[492,498,"PER"],[509,510,"PRON"],[523,526,"PRON"],[534,537,"PRON"],[538,544,"PER"],[553,555,"PRON"],[573,576,"PRON"],[602,608,"PER"],[644,647,"PRON"],[670,673,"PRON"],[674,678,"PER"],[683,691,"GPE"],[693,785,"WORK"],[697,706,"MYTH"],[710,716,"MAT"],[731,739,"FAC"],[762,769,"FAC"],[762,785,"FAC"],[773,785,"FAC"],[792,796,"PROD"],[822,828,"PER"],[836,841,"ORG"],[836,855,"ORG"],[845,855,"PER"],[873,877,"PRON"],[899,902,"PRON"],[920,922,"PRON"],[964,970,"PER"],[975,980,"PER"],[1000,1002,"PRON"],[1049,1052,"PRON"],[1129,1135,"PROD"],[1160,1163,"PRON"],[1205,1208,"PRON"],[1219,1225,"PER"],[1280,1282,"PRON"],[1315,1321,"PER"],[1327,1334,"PER"],[1343,1348,"ORG"],[1371,1373,"PRON"],[1406,1408,"PRON"],[1422,1424,"PRON"],[1446,1448,"PRON"],[1454,1457,"PRON"],[1462,1466,"PROD"],[1498,1503,"PRON"],[1516,1522,"PER"],[1563,1568,"PER"],[1573,1576,"PRON"],[1589,1591,"PRON"],[1661,1668,"PER"],[1696,1702,"PER"],[1714,1718,"PRON"],[1751,1755,"PROD"],[1782,1784,"PRON"],[1840,1842,"PRON"],[1851,1854,"PRON"],[1864,1866,"PRON"],[1872,1874,"PRON"],[1875,1882,"PRON"],[1896,1900,"PRON"],[1918,1920,"PRON"],[1940,1943,"PRON"],[1950,1952,"PRON"]]}
{"id":719,"text":"He died of colic in the year 1430, at the age of forty-seven.","label":[[17,33,"TIME"]]}
{"id":720,"text":"In another niche below this one there are four saints in marble, which the same Nanni was commissioned to make by the Guild of Smiths, Carpenters, and Masons; and it is said that, having finished them all in the round and detached one from another, and having prepared the niche, it was with great difficulty that he could get even three of them into it, for he had made some of them in attitudes with the arms outstretched; and that he besought Donato, in grief and despair, to consent with his counsel to repair his own misfortune and lack of foresight.","label":[[11,16,"FAC"],[42,157,"WORK"],[47,53,"MYTH"],[57,63,"MAT"],[80,85,"PER"],[118,123,"ORG"],[118,157,"ORG"],[127,133,"PER"],[135,145,"PER"],[151,157,"PER"],[273,278,"FAC"],[446,452,"PER"]]}
{"id":721,"text":"It is also reputed that the S. Lo which is without the said Oratory of Orsanmichele, and which was made for the Guild of Farriers, is by the hand of the same Nanni, and likewise the marble shrine, in the base of which, at the foot, there is a scene wherein S. Lo, the Farrier, is shoeing a frenzied horse, so well made that Nanni deserved much praise for it; and he would have deserved and obtained much greater praise with other works, if he had not died, as he did, while still young.","label":[[28,33,"MYTH"],[60,68,"FAC"],[60,83,"FAC"],[71,83,"FAC"],[112,117,"ORG"],[112,129,"ORG"],[121,129,"PER"],[158,163,"PER"],[178,357,"WORK"],[182,188,"MAT"],[189,195,"FAC"],[243,248,"PROD"],[257,275,"MYTH"],[257,304,"MOTIF"],[268,275,"PER"],[299,304,"ANIM"],[324,329,"PER"],[430,435,"PROD"]]}
