{"id":691,"text":"Although there is no truth and not much confidence to be placed in the ancient proverb that the prodigal's purse is never empty, and although, on the contrary, it is very true that he who does not live a well-ordered life in his own degree lives at the last in want and dies miserably, it is seen, nevertheless, that fortune sometimes aids rather those who squander without restraint than those who are in all things careful and self-restrained; and when the favour of fortune ceases, there often comes death, to make up for her defection and for the bad management of men, supervening at the very moment when such men would begin with infinite dismay to recognize how miserable a thing it is to have squandered in youth and to want in old age, living and labouring in poverty, as would have happened to Giovanni da Santo Stefano a Ponte of Florence, if, after having consumed his patrimony and much gain which had been brought to his hands rather by fortune than by his merits, with some inheritances that came to him from an unexpected source, he had not finished at one and the same time the course of his life and all his means. This man, then, who was a disciple of Buonamico Buffalmacco, and who imitated him more in attending to the pleasures of life than in seeking to become an able painter, was born in the year 1307, and after being in early youth a disciple of Buffalmacco, he made his first works in the Chapel of S. Lorenzo, in the Pieve of Empoli, painting there in fresco many scenes of the life of that Saint, with so great diligence that he was summoned to Arezzo in the year 1344, a better development being expected after so fine a beginning; and there he painted the Assumption of Our Lady in a chapel in S. Francesco. And a little time afterwards, being in some credit in that city for lack of other painters, he painted the Chapel of S. Onofrio in the Pieve, with that of S. Antonio, which to-day is spoilt by damp. He also made some other pictures that were in S. Giustina and in S. Matteo, but these were thrown to the ground by Duke Cosimo, together with the said churches, in the making of fortifications for that city; and exactly in that place, at the foot of the abutment of an ancient bridge beside the said S. Giustina, where the stream entered the city, there were then found a head of Appius Cæcus and one of his son, both in marble and very beautiful, with an ancient epitaph, likewise very beautiful, which are all now in the guardaroba[22] of the said Lord Duke. Giovanni, having returned to Florence at the time when there was finished the closing of the middle arch of the Ponte a S. Trinita, painted many figures both within and without a chapel built over one pier and dedicated to S. Michelagnolo, and in particular all the front wall; which chapel, together with the bridge, was carried away by the flood of the year 1557. It is by reason of these works that some maintain, besides what has been said about him at the beginning, that he was ever afterwards called Giovanni dal Ponte. In Pisa, also, in the year 1355, he made some scenes in fresco behind the altar of the principal chapel of S. Paolo a Ripa d'Arno, which are now all spoilt by damp and by time.","label":[[79,86,"PROD"],[160,162,"PRON"],[181,183,"PRON"],[225,228,"PRON"],[286,288,"PRON"],[525,528,"PRON"],[569,572,"PER"],[615,618,"ORG"],[687,689,"PRON"],[804,849,"PER"],[816,837,"GPE"],[841,849,"GPE"],[877,880,"PRON"],[931,934,"PRON"],[967,970,"PRON"],[1015,1018,"PRON"],[1046,1048,"PRON"],[1105,1108,"PRON"],[1122,1125,"PRON"],[1138,1141,"PER"],[1159,1167,"PER"],[1171,1192,"PER"],[1211,1214,"PRON"],[1292,1299,"PER"],[1310,1326,"TIME"],[1361,1369,"PER"],[1373,1384,"PER"],[1386,1388,"PRON"],[1394,1397,"PRON"],[1404,1409,"PROD"],[1417,1423,"FAC"],[1417,1461,"FAC"],[1427,1437,"MYTH"],[1446,1461,"FAC"],[1481,1487,"TECH"],[1488,1525,"WORK"],[1493,1499,"PROD"],[1507,1525,"MOTIF"],[1520,1525,"MYTH"],[1556,1558,"PRON"],[1575,1581,"GPE"],[1585,1598,"TIME"],[1673,1675,"PRON"],[1684,1738,"WORK"],[1688,1710,"MYTH"],[1702,1710,"MYTH"],[1716,1722,"FAC"],[1726,1738,"FAC"],[1799,1803,"GPE"],[1822,1830,"PER"],[1832,1834,"PRON"],[1847,1853,"FAC"],[1847,1880,"FAC"],[1857,1867,"MYTH"],[1875,1880,"GPE"],[1895,1905,"MOTIF"],[1895,1905,"MYTH"],[1895,1905,"WORK"],[1939,1941,"PRON"],[1963,1971,"PROD"],[1984,1996,"FAC"],[2004,2013,"FAC"],[2054,2058,"PER"],[2054,2058,"PER"],[2054,2065,"PER"],[2054,2065,"PER"],[2090,2098,"FAC"],[2117,2131,"FAC"],[2141,2145,"GPE"],[2216,2222,"FAC"],[2239,2250,"FAC"],[2281,2285,"GPE"],[2319,2331,"PER"],[2343,2346,"PRON"],[2347,2350,"PER"],[2360,2366,"MAT"],[2403,2410,"PROD"],[2462,2472,"FAC"],[2489,2493,"PER"],[2489,2498,"PER"],[2494,2498,"PER"],[2500,2508,"PER"],[2529,2537,"GPE"],[2538,2630,"TIME"],[2600,2604,"FAC"],[2612,2630,"FAC"],[2620,2630,"MYTH"],[2645,2652,"PROD"],[2679,2685,"FAC"],[2701,2705,"FAC"],[2723,2738,"PER"],[2772,2776,"FAC"],[2784,2790,"FAC"],[2810,2816,"FAC"],[2838,2864,"EVE"],[2838,2864,"TIME"],[2866,2868,"PRON"],[2891,2896,"PROD"],[2977,2979,"PRON"],[3007,3025,"PER"],[3030,3034,"GPE"],[3042,3058,"TIME"],[3060,3062,"PRON"],[3073,3079,"PROD"],[3083,3089,"TECH"],[3101,3106,"FAC"],[3124,3130,"FAC"],[3134,3142,"MYTH"],[3134,3156,"FAC"],[3145,3156,"GPE"]]}
{"id":692,"text":"Giovanni also painted the Chapel of the Scali in S. Trinita in Florence, with another that is beside it, and one of the stories of S. Paul by the side of the principal chapel, where is the tomb of Maestro Paolo, the astrologer.","label":[[0,8,"PER"],[26,32,"FAC"],[26,71,"FAC"],[40,45,"ORG"],[49,71,"FAC"],[109,226,"WORK"],[120,127,"PROD"],[120,138,"MOTIF"],[131,138,"MYTH"],[168,174,"FAC"],[189,193,"FAC"],[197,227,"PER"]]}
