{"id":735,"text":"How bountiful and benign Heaven sometimes shows itself in showering upon one single person the infinite riches of its treasures, and all those graces and rarest gifts that it is wont to distribute among many individuals, over a long space of time, could be clearly seen in the no less excellent than gracious Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino, who was endowed by nature with all that modesty and goodness which are seen at times in those who, beyond all other men, have added to their natural sweetness and gentleness the beautiful adornment of courtesy and grace, by reason of which they always show themselves agreeable and pleasant to every sort of person and in all their actions. Him nature presented to the world, when, vanquished by art through the hands of Michelagnolo Buonarroti, she wished to be vanquished, in Raffaello, by art and character together. And in truth, since the greater part of the craftsmen who had lived up to that time had received from nature a certain element of savagery and madness, which, besides making them strange and eccentric, had brought it about that very often there was revealed in them rather the obscure darkness of vice than the brightness and splendour of those virtues that make men immortal, there was right good reason for her to cause to shine out brilliantly in Raffaello, as a contrast to the others, all the rarest qualities of the mind, accompanied by such grace, industry, beauty, modesty, and excellence of character, as would have sufficed to efface any vice, however hideous, and any blot, were it ever so great. Wherefore it may be surely said that those who are the possessors of such rare and numerous gifts as were seen in Raffaello da Urbino, are not merely men, but, if it be not a sin to say it, mortal gods;  and that those who, by means of their works, leave an honourable name written in the archives of fame in this earthly world of ours, can also hope to have to enjoy in Heaven a worthy reward for their labours and merits. RAPHAEL: S. GEORGE AND THE DRAGON (S. Petersburg: Hermitage, 39. Panel) View larger image Raffaello was born at Urbino, a very famous city in Italy, at three o'clock of the night on Good Friday, in the year 1483, to a father named Giovanni de' Santi, a painter of no great excellence, and yet a man of good intelligence, well able to direct his children on that good path which he himself had not been fortunate enough to have shown to him in his boyhood. And since Giovanni knew how important it is to rear infants, not with the milk of nurses, but with that of their own mothers, no sooner was Raffaello born, to whom with happy augury he gave that name at baptism, than he insisted that this his only child—and he had no more afterwards—should be suckled by his own mother, and that in his tender years he should have his character formed in the house of his parents, rather than learn less gentle or even boorish ways and habits in the houses of peasants or common people.","label":[[25,31,"MYTH"],[48,54,"PRON"],[84,90,"PER"],[114,117,"PRON"],[118,127,"PROD"],[172,174,"PRON"],[208,219,"PER"],[309,335,"PER"],[329,335,"GPE"],[453,456,"PER"],[472,477,"PRON"],[525,534,"PROD"],[577,581,"PRON"],[645,651,"PER"],[663,668,"PRON"],[669,676,"PROD"],[678,681,"PRON"],[682,688,"LOC"],[706,711,"LOC"],[733,736,"PROD"],[758,781,"PER"],[783,786,"PRON"],[815,824,"PER"],[829,832,"PROD"],[901,910,"PER"],[959,965,"LOC"],[1031,1035,"PRON"],[1071,1073,"PRON"],[1118,1122,"PRON"],[1202,1209,"MYTH"],[1220,1223,"PER"],[1266,1268,"PRON"],[1307,1316,"PER"],[1547,1549,"PRON"],[1575,1577,"PRON"],[1679,1698,"PER"],[1692,1698,"GPE"],[1715,1718,"PER"],[1728,1730,"PRON"],[1751,1753,"PRON"],[1755,1766,"MYTH"],[1762,1766,"MYTH"],[1807,1812,"PROD"],[1854,1862,"FAC"],[1887,1892,"GPE"],[1896,1900,"PRON"],[1936,1942,"MYTH"],[1989,1996,"PER"],[1998,2007,"MYTH"],[1998,2022,"MOTIF"],[1998,2022,"WORK"],[2016,2022,"MYTH"],[2079,2088,"PER"],[2101,2136,"GPE"],[2123,2127,"GPE"],[2131,2136,"GPE"],[2168,2200,"TIME"],[2207,2213,"PER"],[2207,2272,"PER"],[2242,2249,"PER"],[2284,2287,"PER"],[2330,2333,"PRON"],[2334,2342,"PER"],[2367,2369,"PRON"],[2370,2377,"PRON"],[2425,2428,"PRON"],[2432,2435,"PRON"],[2436,2443,"PER"],[2455,2463,"PER"],[2483,2485,"PRON"],[2497,2504,"PER"],[2527,2533,"PER"],[2562,2569,"PER"],[2585,2594,"PER"],[2627,2629,"PRON"],[2648,2655,"MYTH"],[2662,2664,"PRON"],[2684,2687,"PRON"],[2693,2698,"PER"],[2703,2705,"PRON"],[2750,2753,"PRON"],[2758,2764,"PER"],[2778,2781,"PRON"],[2795,2797,"PRON"],[2810,2813,"PRON"],[2838,2843,"FAC"],[2847,2850,"PRON"],[2851,2858,"PER"],[2929,2935,"FAC"],[2939,2947,"PER"],[2958,2964,"PER"]]}
{"id":736,"text":"This picture was held by Lorenzo Nasi, as long as he lived, in very great veneration, both in memory of Raffaello, who had been so much his friend, and on account of the dignity and excellence of the work; but afterwards, on August 9, in the year 1548, it met an evil fate, when, on account of the collapse of the hill of S. Giorgio, the house of Lorenzo fell down, together with the ornate and beautiful houses of the heirs of Marco del Nero, and other neighbouring dwellings.","label":[[5,12,"PROD"],[25,37,"PER"],[104,113,"PER"],[140,146,"PER"],[200,204,"PROD"],[225,251,"TIME"],[298,332,"EVE"],[314,318,"GPE"],[322,332,"GPE"],[338,343,"FAC"],[347,354,"PER"],[405,411,"FAC"],[419,424,"PER"],[428,442,"PER"],[467,476,"FAC"]]}
{"id":737,"text":"In one was the Burning of the Borgo Vecchio of Rome, when, all other methods having failed to put out the fire, S. Leo IV presents himself at the Loggia of his Palace and extinguishes it completely with his benediction.","label":[[11,218,"WORK"],[15,22,"EVE"],[15,51,"EVE"],[15,51,"TIME"],[15,218,"MOTIF"],[30,43,"GPE"],[47,51,"GPE"],[112,121,"MYTH"],[146,152,"FAC"],[160,166,"FAC"],[207,218,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":738,"text":"After this work, Pietro returning to Florence on some business of his own, Raffaello departed from Perugia and went off with some friends to Città di Castello, where he painted a panel for S. Agostino in the same manner, and likewise one of a Crucifixion for S. Domenico, which, if his name were not written upon it, no one would believe to be a work by Raffaello, but rather by Pietro.","label":[[11,15,"PROD"],[17,23,"PER"],[37,45,"GPE"],[75,84,"PER"],[99,106,"GPE"],[141,158,"GPE"],[177,200,"WORK"],[179,184,"PROD"],[189,200,"FAC"],[241,385,"WORK"],[243,254,"MYTH"],[259,270,"FAC"],[346,350,"PROD"],[354,363,"PER"],[379,385,"PER"]]}
{"id":739,"text":"Raffaello also formed a very great friendship with Lorenzo Nasi; and for this Lorenzo, who had taken a wife about that time, he painted a picture in which he made a Madonna, and between her legs her Son, to whom a little S. John, full of joy, is offering a bird, with great delight and pleasure for both of them.","label":[[0,9,"PER"],[51,63,"PER"],[78,85,"PER"],[103,107,"PER"],[136,311,"WORK"],[138,145,"PROD"],[165,172,"MYTH"],[165,311,"MOTIF"],[199,202,"MYTH"],[214,241,"MYTH"],[257,261,"ANIM"]]}
{"id":740,"text":"Not long after this, Agostino Chigi, a very rich merchant of Siena, who was much the friend of every man of excellence, gave Raffaello the commission to paint a chapel; and this he did because a short time before Raffaello had painted for him in his softest manner, in a loggia of his palace, now called the Chigi, in the Trastevere, a Galatea in a car on the sea drawn by two dolphins, and surrounded by Tritons and many sea-gods.","label":[[21,35,"PER"],[61,66,"GPE"],[85,91,"PER"],[101,104,"PER"],[125,134,"PER"],[161,167,"FAC"],[213,222,"PER"],[271,277,"FAC"],[285,291,"FAC"],[308,332,"FAC"],[322,332,"GPE"],[334,430,"WORK"],[336,343,"MYTH"],[336,430,"MOTIF"],[349,352,"PROD"],[360,363,"GPE"],[377,385,"ANIM"],[405,412,"MYTH"],[422,430,"MYTH"]]}
