{"id":712,"text":"While the most noble and industrious spirits were striving, by the light of the famous Giotto and of his followers, to give to the world a proof of the ability that the benign influence of the stars and the proportionate admixture of humours had given to their intellects, and while, desirous to imitate with the excellence of their art the grandeur of Nature in order to approach as near as possible to that supreme knowledge that many call understanding, they were universally toiling, although in vain, the most benign Ruler of Heaven in His clemency turned His eyes to the earth, and, having perceived the infinite vanity of all those labours, the ardent studies without any fruit, and the presumptuous self-sufficiency of men, which is even further removed from truth than is darkness from light, and desiring to deliver us from such great errors, became minded to send down to earth a spirit with universal ability in every art and every profession, who might be able, working by himself alone, to show what manner of thing is the perfection of the art of design in executing the lines, contours, shadows, and high lights, so as to give relief to works of painting, and what it is to work with correct judgment in sculpture, and how in architecture it is possible to render habitations secure and commodious, healthy and cheerful, well-proportioned, and rich with varied ornaments. He was pleased, in addition, to endow him with the true moral philosophy and with the ornament of sweet poesy, to the end that the world might choose him and admire him as its highest exemplar in the life, works, saintliness of character, and every action of human creatures, and that he might be acclaimed by us as a being rather divine than human. And since He saw that in the practice of these rare exercises  and arts—namely, in painting, in sculpture, and in architecture—the Tuscan intellects have always been exalted and raised high above all others, from their being diligent in the labours and studies of every faculty beyond no matter what other people of Italy, He chose to give him Florence, as worthy beyond all other cities, for his country, in order to bring all the talents to their highest perfection in her, as was her due, in the person of one of her citizens. MICHELAGNOLO BUONARROTI: THE HOLY FAMILY (Florence: Uffizi, 1239. Panel) View larger image There was born a son, then, in the Casentino, in the year 1474, under a fateful and happy star, from an excellent and noble mother, to Lodovico di Leonardo Buonarroti Simoni, a descendant, so it is said, of the most noble and most ancient family of the Counts of Canossa. To that Lodovico, I say, who was in that year Podestà of the township of Chiusi and Caprese, near the Sasso della Vernia, where S. Francis received the Stigmata, in the Diocese of Arezzo, a son was born on the 6th of March, a Sunday, about the eighth hour of the night, to which son he gave the name Michelagnolo, because, inspired by some influence from above, and giving it no more thought, he wished to suggest that he was something celestial and divine beyond the use of mortals, as was afterwards seen from the figures of his horoscope, he having had Mercury and Venus in the second house of Jupiter, with happy augury, which showed that from the art of his brain and of his hand there would be seen to issue forth works marvellous and stupendous. Having finished his office as Podestà, Lodovico returned to Florence and settled in the village of Settignano, at a distance of three miles from the city, where he had a farm that had belonged to his forefathers; which place abounds with stone and is all full of quarries of grey-stone, which is constantly being worked by stone-cutters and sculptors, who for the most part are born in the place.","label":[[87,93,"PER"],[101,104,"PRON"],[105,114,"PER"],[131,136,"GPE"],[255,260,"PRON"],[327,332,"PRON"],[353,359,"MYTH"],[457,461,"PRON"],[522,537,"MYTH"],[531,537,"MYTH"],[541,544,"PRON"],[561,564,"PRON"],[577,582,"GPE"],[679,684,"PLANT"],[727,730,"PER"],[826,828,"PRON"],[883,888,"LOC"],[891,897,"MYTH"],[930,933,"PROD"],[944,954,"PROD"],[986,993,"PRON"],[1055,1058,"PROD"],[1062,1068,"PROD"],[1153,1158,"PROD"],[1162,1170,"PROD"],[1181,1183,"PRON"],[1220,1229,"PROD"],[1242,1254,"PROD"],[1255,1257,"PRON"],[1280,1291,"FAC"],[1377,1386,"PROD"],[1388,1390,"PRON"],[1426,1429,"PRON"],[1450,1460,"PROD"],[1474,1482,"PROD"],[1492,1497,"PROD"],[1519,1524,"GPE"],[1538,1541,"PRON"],[1553,1556,"PRON"],[1560,1563,"PRON"],[1594,1599,"PROD"],[1653,1662,"ANIM"],[1673,1675,"PRON"],[1698,1700,"PRON"],[1748,1750,"PRON"],[1805,1809,"PROD"],[1834,1843,"PROD"],[1852,1864,"PROD"],[1869,1875,"GPE"],[1876,1886,"PER"],[2054,2059,"GPE"],[2061,2063,"PRON"],[2078,2081,"PRON"],[2082,2090,"GPE"],[2119,2125,"GPE"],[2131,2134,"PRON"],[2135,2142,"GPE"],[2181,2186,"PRON"],[2209,2212,"PRON"],[2221,2224,"PRON"],[2254,2257,"PRON"],[2258,2266,"PER"],[2268,2291,"PER"],[2293,2308,"PROD"],[2293,2308,"WORK"],[2297,2308,"MOTIF"],[2297,2308,"MYTH"],[2376,2379,"PER"],[2394,2403,"GPE"],[2405,2421,"TIME"],[2483,2489,"PER"],[2494,2629,"PER"],[2536,2546,"PER"],[2551,2553,"PRON"],[2598,2604,"ORG"],[2612,2629,"ORG"],[2639,2647,"PER"],[2649,2650,"PRON"],[2664,2676,"TIME"],[2677,2684,"PER"],[2692,2700,"GPE"],[2692,2710,"GPE"],[2715,2722,"GPE"],[2733,2751,"GPE"],[2759,2769,"MYTH"],[2783,2791,"MYTH"],[2800,2817,"MYTH"],[2811,2817,"GPE"],[2821,2824,"PER"],[2834,2863,"TIME"],[2914,2916,"PRON"],[2931,2943,"PER"],[3004,3006,"PRON"],[3024,3026,"PRON"],[3050,3052,"PRON"],[3147,3154,"PROD"],[3158,3161,"PRON"],[3162,3171,"MYTH"],[3173,3175,"PRON"],[3187,3194,"MYTH"],[3199,3204,"MYTH"],[3219,3224,"FAC"],[3228,3235,"MYTH"],[3283,3286,"PROD"],[3290,3293,"PRON"],[3307,3310,"PRON"],[3351,3356,"PROD"],[3400,3403,"PRON"],[3414,3421,"PER"],[3423,3431,"PER"],[3444,3452,"GPE"],[3472,3479,"GPE"],[3472,3493,"GPE"],[3533,3537,"GPE"],[3545,3547,"PRON"],[3554,3558,"FAC"],[3580,3583,"PRON"],[3584,3595,"PER"],[3622,3627,"MAT"],[3647,3655,"FAC"],[3659,3669,"MAT"],[3707,3720,"PER"],[3725,3734,"PER"],[3774,3779,"LOC"]]}
{"id":713,"text":"That entry runs thus: \"1488, I record, this first day of April, that I, Lodovico di Leonardo di Buonarrota, placed Michelagnolo my son with Domenico and David di Tommaso di Currado for the three years next to come, on these terms and conditions, that the said Michelagnolo shall remain with the above-named persons for the said period  of time, in order to learn to paint and to exercise that vocation; that the said persons shall have command over him; and that the same Domenico and David shall be bound to give him in those three years twenty-four florins of full weight, the first year six florins, the second year eight florins, and the third ten florins; in all, the sum of ninety-six lire.\"","label":[[23,27,"TIME"],[39,62,"TIME"],[72,106,"PER"],[84,106,"PER"],[115,127,"PER"],[131,134,"PER"],[140,148,"PER"],[153,180,"PER"],[181,213,"TIME"],[260,272,"PER"],[307,314,"PER"],[417,424,"PER"],[472,480,"PER"],[485,490,"PER"],[527,538,"PRON"]]}
{"id":714,"text":"In the year 1549 there took place the death of Pope Paul III; whereupon, after the election of Pope Julius III, Cardinal Farnese gave orders for a grand tomb to be made for his kinsman Pope Paul by the hand of Fra Guglielmo, who arranged to erect it in S. Pietro, below the first arch of the new church, beneath the tribune, which obstructed the floor of the church, and was, in truth, not the proper place.","label":[[0,16,"TIME"],[34,60,"TIME"],[73,110,"TIME"],[177,184,"PER"],[185,189,"MYTH"],[185,194,"MYTH"],[210,223,"MYTH"],[253,262,"FAC"],[280,284,"FAC"],[296,302,"FAC"],[316,323,"FAC"],[346,351,"FAC"],[359,365,"FAC"]]}
{"id":715,"text":"And so, also, do men marvel at the beautiful attitudes that Michelagnolo depicted in the story of Judith, at the opposite corner, in which may be seen the trunk of Holofernes, robbed of life but still quivering, while Judith is placing the lifeless head in a basket on the head of her old serving-woman, who, being tall in stature, is stooping to the end that Judith may be able to reach up to her and adjust the weight well; and the servant, while upholding the burden with her hands, seeks to conceal it, and, turning her head towards the trunk, which, although dead, draws up an arm and a leg and makes a noise in the tent, she shows in her expression fear of the camp and terror of the dead body—a picture truly full of thought.","label":[[17,20,"PER"],[60,72,"PER"],[85,731,"WORK"],[89,94,"PROD"],[89,104,"MOTIF"],[89,104,"MYTH"],[98,104,"MYTH"],[155,699,"MOTIF"],[164,174,"MYTH"],[218,224,"MYTH"],[259,265,"PROD"],[360,366,"MYTH"],[434,441,"PER"],[621,625,"FAC"],[702,709,"PROD"]]}
{"id":716,"text":"For the Church of S. Spirito in the city of Florence Michelagnolo made a Crucifix of wood, which was placed, as it still is, above the lunette of the high-altar; doing this to please the Prior, who placed rooms at his disposal, in which he was constantly flaying dead bodies, in order to study the secrets of anatomy, thus beginning to give perfection to the great knowledge of design that he afterwards acquired.","label":[[8,14,"FAC"],[8,28,"FAC"],[18,28,"MYTH"],[36,40,"GPE"],[36,52,"GPE"],[53,65,"PER"],[71,160,"WORK"],[73,81,"MYTH"],[85,89,"MAT"],[135,142,"FAC"],[150,160,"FAC"],[187,192,"MYTH"],[205,210,"FAC"],[309,316,"PROD"],[378,384,"PROD"]]}
{"id":717,"text":"The figure of Haman was executed by Michelagnolo in an extraordinary manner of foreshortening, for he counterfeited the trunk that supports his person, and that arm which comes forward, not as painted things but as real and natural, standing out in relief, and so also that leg which he stretches outwards and other parts that bend inwards: which figure, among all that are beautiful and difficult, is certainly the most beautiful and the most difficult.","label":[[0,19,"WORK"],[4,10,"PROD"],[14,19,"MYTH"],[36,48,"PER"],[144,150,"PER"],[347,353,"PROD"]]}
