{"id":653,"text":"There is now living in Rome one who is certainly very excellent in his profession, Girolamo Siciolante of Sermoneta, of whom, although something has been said in the Life of Perino del Vaga, whose disciple he was, assisting him in the works of Castel S. Angelo and in many others, nevertheless it cannot but be well to say also here so much as his great excellence truly deserves. Among the first works, then, that this Girolamo executed by himself, was an altar-piece twelve palms high painted by him in oils at the age of twenty, which is now in the Badia of S. Stefano, near his native town of Sermoneta; wherein, large as life, are S. Peter, S. Stephen, and S. John the Baptist, with certain children. After that altar-piece, which was much extolled, he painted for the Church of S. Apostolo, in Rome, an altar-piece in oils with the Dead Christ, Our Lady, S. John, the Magdalene, and other figures, all executed with diligence. Then in the Pace, in the marble chapel that Cardinal Cesis caused to be constructed, he decorated the whole vaulting with stucco-work in a pattern of four pictures, painting therein the Nativity of Jesus Christ, the Adoration of the Magi, the Flight into Egypt, and the Massacre of the Innocents; all which was a work worthy of much praise and executed with invention, judgment, and diligence. For that same church, not long after, the same Girolamo painted an altar-piece fifteen palms high, which is beside the high-altar, of the Nativity of Jesus Christ, which was very beautiful; and then in another altar-piece in oils, for the Sacristy of the Church of S. Spirito in Rome, the Descent of the Holy Spirit upon the Apostles, which is a work full of grace. In like manner, in the Church of S. Maria de Anima, the church of the German colony, he painted in fresco the whole of the Chapel of the Fugger family (for which  Giulio Romano once executed the altar-piece), with large scenes of the Life of Our Lady. For the high-altar of S. Jacopo degli Spagnuoli he painted in a large altar-piece a very beautiful Christ on the Cross with some Angels about Him, Our Lady, and S. John, and besides this two large pictures that are one on either side of it, each nine palms high and with a single figure, S. James the Apostle and S. Alfonso the Bishop; in which pictures it is evident that he used much study and diligence.","label":[[23,27,"GPE"],[67,70,"PRON"],[83,115,"PER"],[106,115,"GPE"],[166,170,"PROD"],[174,189,"PER"],[197,205,"PER"],[206,208,"PRON"],[224,227,"PRON"],[235,240,"PROD"],[244,250,"FAC"],[244,260,"FAC"],[251,260,"PER"],[294,296,"PRON"],[344,347,"PRON"],[397,402,"PROD"],[420,428,"PER"],[441,448,"PRON"],[454,704,"WORK"],[457,468,"PROD"],[498,501,"PRON"],[505,509,"TECH"],[552,557,"FAC"],[552,571,"FAC"],[561,571,"PER"],[578,581,"PRON"],[589,593,"GPE"],[589,606,"GPE"],[636,644,"PER"],[636,704,"MOTIF"],[646,656,"PER"],[662,681,"PER"],[674,681,"PER"],[696,704,"PER"],[696,704,"PER"],[717,728,"PROD"],[755,757,"PRON"],[774,780,"FAC"],[774,804,"FAC"],[784,795,"MYTH"],[800,804,"GPE"],[806,931,"WORK"],[809,820,"PROD"],[824,828,"TECH"],[838,849,"MYTH"],[838,902,"MOTIF"],[843,849,"MYTH"],[851,859,"MYTH"],[861,868,"MYTH"],[874,883,"MYTH"],[895,902,"PROD"],[945,949,"FAC"],[958,964,"MAT"],[965,971,"FAC"],[977,985,"MYTH"],[977,991,"MYTH"],[1018,1020,"PRON"],[1041,1049,"LOC"],[1055,1066,"TECH"],[1072,1079,"PROD"],[1088,1096,"PROD"],[1115,1143,"WORK"],[1119,1143,"MOTIF"],[1119,1143,"MYTH"],[1131,1143,"MYTH"],[1145,1170,"WORK"],[1149,1170,"MOTIF"],[1149,1170,"MYTH"],[1166,1170,"MYTH"],[1172,1193,"WORK"],[1176,1193,"MOTIF"],[1176,1193,"MYTH"],[1188,1193,"GPE"],[1199,1228,"WORK"],[1203,1228,"MOTIF"],[1203,1228,"MYTH"],[1246,1250,"PROD"],[1341,1347,"FAC"],[1374,1382,"PER"],[1391,1489,"WORK"],[1394,1405,"PROD"],[1446,1456,"LOC"],[1465,1489,"MYTH"],[1477,1489,"MYTH"],[1537,1548,"PROD"],[1552,1556,"TECH"],[1566,1574,"LOC"],[1582,1588,"FAC"],[1582,1610,"FAC"],[1592,1602,"MYTH"],[1606,1610,"GPE"],[1612,1691,"WORK"],[1616,1660,"MOTIF"],[1616,1660,"MYTH"],[1631,1642,"MYTH"],[1652,1660,"PER"],[1716,1722,"FAC"],[1716,1776,"FAC"],[1726,1743,"PER"],[1749,1755,"FAC"],[1763,1776,"ORG"],[1778,1780,"PRON"],[1792,1798,"TECH"],[1816,1822,"FAC"],[1816,1843,"FAC"],[1830,1843,"ORG"],[1856,1869,"PER"],[1888,1899,"PROD"],[1907,1943,"WORK"],[1913,1919,"PROD"],[1927,1943,"MOTIF"],[1935,1943,"PER"],[1953,1963,"FAC"],[1967,1976,"PER"],[1967,1992,"FAC"],[1993,1995,"PRON"],[2015,2026,"PROD"],[2027,2113,"WORK"],[2044,2050,"PER"],[2044,2113,"MOTIF"],[2058,2063,"PROD"],[2074,2080,"PRON"],[2092,2100,"PER"],[2106,2113,"PER"],[2142,2150,"PROD"],[2182,2184,"PRON"],[2233,2253,"MOTIF"],[2233,2253,"PER"],[2233,2253,"WORK"],[2246,2253,"PER"],[2258,2279,"MOTIF"],[2258,2279,"PER"],[2258,2279,"WORK"],[2273,2279,"PER"],[2290,2298,"PROD"],[2299,2301,"PRON"],[2318,2320,"PRON"]]}
{"id":654,"text":"In the Hall of Kings, at the time of Pope Pius IV, as has been related, he executed a scene in fresco over the door of the Chapel of Sixtus; in that scene, which was much extolled, Pepin, King of the Franks, is presenting Ravenna to the Roman Church, and is leading as prisoner Astulf, King of the Lombards; and we have the design of it by Girolamo's own hand  in our book, with many others by the same master.","label":[[7,11,"LOC"],[7,20,"LOC"],[15,20,"PER"],[25,49,"TIME"],[37,41,"MYTH"],[37,49,"MYTH"],[84,409,"WORK"],[86,91,"PROD"],[95,101,"TECH"],[111,115,"LOC"],[123,129,"FAC"],[123,139,"FAC"],[133,139,"PER"],[149,154,"PROD"],[181,206,"PER"],[181,306,"MOTIF"],[188,192,"PER"],[200,206,"PER"],[222,229,"GPE"],[237,249,"MYTH"],[243,249,"FAC"],[269,277,"PER"],[278,306,"PER"],[286,290,"PER"],[298,306,"PER"],[324,330,"PROD"],[340,348,"PER"],[368,372,"PROD"],[403,409,"PER"]]}
{"id":655,"text":"Of his portraits—not to speak of them all, which would make a very long story—I shall say only that he has portrayed all the Pontiffs that there have been from Pope Paul III to the present day, and all the lords and ambassadors of importance who have been at that Court, and likewise the military captains and great men of the house of Colonna and of the Orsini, Signor Piero Strozzi, and an infinite number of Bishops, Cardinals, and other great prelates and lords, not to speak of many men of letters and other men of quality; all which has caused him to acquire fame, honour, and profit in Rome, so that he lives honourably and much at his ease with his family in that city.","label":[[7,16,"PROD"],[125,133,"MYTH"],[155,192,"TIME"],[160,164,"MYTH"],[160,173,"MYTH"],[206,211,"PER"],[216,227,"PER"],[264,269,"LOC"],[288,305,"PER"],[297,305,"PER"],[310,319,"PER"],[316,319,"PER"],[327,343,"ORG"],[355,361,"ORG"],[363,369,"PER"],[363,383,"PER"],[411,418,"MYTH"],[420,429,"MYTH"],[447,455,"MYTH"],[460,465,"PER"],[488,491,"PER"],[495,502,"PROD"],[513,516,"PER"],[593,597,"GPE"],[657,663,"PROD"],[672,676,"GPE"]]}
{"id":656,"text":"Having said above, in the Life of Perino del Vaga, that the painter Marcello Mantovano worked many years under him at pictures that gave him a great name, I have to say in this place, coming more to particulars, that he once painted in the Church of S. Spirito the whole Chapel of S. Giovanni Evangelista and its altar-piece, with the portrait of a Knight Commander of the same S. Spirito, who built that church and constructed that chapel; which portrait is a very good likeness, and the altar-piece most beautiful.","label":[[34,49,"PER"],[60,67,"PER"],[60,86,"PER"],[118,126,"PROD"],[240,246,"FAC"],[240,260,"FAC"],[250,260,"GPE"],[271,277,"FAC"],[271,304,"FAC"],[281,304,"PER"],[313,324,"PROD"],[335,343,"PROD"],[335,515,"WORK"],[349,365,"PER"],[378,388,"GPE"],[405,412,"FAC"],[433,439,"FAC"],[447,455,"PROD"],[489,500,"PROD"]]}
