{"id":646,"text":"While Giorgione and Correggio, to their own great credit and glory, were honouring the regions of Lombardy, Tuscany, on her part, was not wanting in men of beautiful intellect; among whom, not one of the least was Piero, the son of one Lorenzo, a goldsmith, and a pupil of Cosimo Rosselli, after whom he was always called Piero di Cosimo, and known by no other name. And in truth, when a man teaches us excellence and gives us the secret of living rightly, he deserves no less gratitude from us, and should be held no less as a true father, than he who begets us and gives us life and nothing more. Piero was entrusted by his father, who saw in his son a lively intelligence and an inclination to the art of design, to the care of Cosimo, who took him with no ordinary willingness; and seeing him grow no less in ability than in years, among the many disciples that he had, he bore him love as to a son, and always held him as such. This young man had by nature a most lofty spirit, and he was very strange, and different in fancy from the other youths who were working with Cosimo in order to learn the same art. He was at times so intent on what he was doing, that when some subject was being discussed, as often happens, at the end of the discussion it was necessary to go back to the beginning and tell him the whole, so far had his brain wandered after some other fancy of his own. And he was likewise so great a lover of solitude, that he knew no pleasure save that of going off by himself with his thoughts, letting his fancy roam and building his castles in the air. Right good reason had Cosimo, his master, for wishing him well, seeing that he made so much use of him in his works, that very often he caused him to execute  things of great importance, knowing that Piero had a more beautiful manner, as well as better judgment, than himself.","label":[[6,15,"PER"],[20,29,"PER"],[34,39,"PRON"],[87,94,"GPE"],[87,106,"GPE"],[108,115,"GPE"],[120,123,"PRON"],[149,152,"PER"],[214,288,"PER"],[225,228,"PER"],[236,256,"PER"],[264,269,"PER"],[273,288,"PER"],[301,303,"PRON"],[322,337,"PER"],[388,391,"PER"],[400,402,"PRON"],[457,459,"PRON"],[492,494,"PRON"],[533,539,"PER"],[546,548,"PRON"],[560,562,"PRON"],[573,575,"PRON"],[599,604,"PER"],[622,625,"PRON"],[626,632,"PER"],[645,648,"PRON"],[649,652,"PER"],[708,714,"PROD"],[731,737,"PER"],[748,751,"PRON"],[793,796,"PRON"],[851,860,"PER"],[866,868,"PRON"],[882,885,"PRON"],[899,902,"PER"],[920,923,"PRON"],[938,947,"PER"],[944,947,"PER"],[987,989,"PRON"],[1046,1052,"PER"],[1075,1081,"PER"],[1148,1150,"PRON"],[1253,1255,"PRON"],[1307,1310,"PRON"],[1333,1336,"PRON"],[1378,1381,"PRON"],[1391,1393,"PRON"],[1442,1444,"PRON"],[1501,1504,"PRON"],[1523,1526,"PRON"],[1551,1554,"PRON"],[1555,1562,"FAC"],[1597,1603,"PER"],[1605,1608,"PRON"],[1629,1632,"PRON"],[1651,1653,"PRON"],[1674,1677,"PRON"],[1681,1684,"PRON"],[1685,1690,"PROD"],[1708,1710,"PRON"],[1718,1721,"PRON"],[1775,1780,"PER"],[1843,1850,"PRON"]]}
{"id":647,"text":"I have heard from the lips of Andrea di Cosimo, who helped him to carry out the work, and of Andrea del Sarto, who was Piero's disciple, and who also had a hand in it, that it was a common opinion at that time that this invention was intended to foreshadow the return of the Medici family to Florence in the year 1512, since at the time when the procession was held they were exiles, and, so to speak, dead, but destined in a short time to come to life; and in this sense were interpreted the following words in the song—","label":[[30,46,"PER"],[80,84,"PROD"],[93,109,"PER"],[119,124,"PER"],[127,135,"PER"],[220,229,"PROD"],[275,288,"PER"],[282,288,"PER"],[292,300,"GPE"],[301,317,"TIME"],[516,520,"PROD"]]}
{"id":648,"text":"Wherefore, living in such strange fashion, he reduced himself to such a state with his extravagant fancies, that one morning he was found dead at the foot of a staircase, in the year 1521; and he was given burial in S. Piero Maggiore.","label":[[160,169,"FAC"],[171,187,"TIME"],[216,224,"MYTH"],[216,233,"FAC"]]}
{"id":649,"text":"These scenes, after the death of Francesco del Pugliese and his sons, were taken away, nor do I know what has become of them; and the same thing has happened to a picture of Mars and Venus, with her Loves and Vulcan, executed with great art and with an incredible patience.","label":[[14,68,"TIME"],[24,29,"EVE"],[33,55,"PER"],[64,68,"PER"],[161,272,"WORK"],[163,170,"PROD"],[174,178,"MYTH"],[174,215,"MOTIF"],[183,188,"MYTH"],[199,204,"MYTH"],[209,215,"MYTH"],[237,240,"PROD"]]}
{"id":650,"text":"Piero painted, for the elder Filippo Strozzi, a picture with little figures of Perseus delivering Andromeda from the Monster, in which are some very beautiful things.","label":[[0,5,"PER"],[23,44,"PER"],[46,165,"WORK"],[48,55,"PROD"],[79,86,"MYTH"],[79,124,"MOTIF"],[98,107,"MYTH"],[117,124,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":651,"text":"But to return to the art and actions of Piero; he was given the commission for a panel in the Church of the Servite Friars, in the Chapel of the Tedaldi, where they keep the garment and the pillow of S. Filippo, a brother of their Order; wherein he depicted Our Lady standing, raised from the ground on a pedestal, and uplifting her head towards Heaven, with a book in her hand, but without her Son; and above her is the Holy Spirit, bathing her with light.","label":[[40,45,"PER"],[64,74,"PROD"],[79,456,"WORK"],[81,86,"PROD"],[94,100,"FAC"],[94,122,"FAC"],[108,122,"MYTH"],[131,137,"FAC"],[131,152,"FAC"],[145,152,"FAC"],[174,181,"PROD"],[190,196,"PROD"],[200,210,"MYTH"],[214,221,"MYTH"],[231,236,"MYTH"],[258,266,"MYTH"],[258,456,"MOTIF"],[293,299,"GPE"],[305,313,"PROD"],[346,352,"MYTH"],[361,365,"PROD"],[395,398,"MYTH"],[421,432,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":652,"text":"The Director of the Hospital of the Innocenti was much the friend of Piero; and wishing to have a panel painted, which was to be placed in the Pugliese Chapel, near the entrance into the church, on the left hand, he gave the commission for it to Piero, who brought it to completion at his leisure; but first he reduced his patron to despair, for on no account would he let him see it until it was finished.","label":[[4,12,"PER"],[4,45,"PER"],[20,45,"FAC"],[59,65,"PER"],[69,74,"PER"],[98,103,"PROD"],[143,158,"FAC"],[152,158,"FAC"],[187,193,"FAC"],[246,251,"PER"],[323,329,"PER"]]}
