{"id":693,"text":"Great, indeed, is the good fortune of those craftsmen who are brought into contact, either by their birth or by the associations that are formed in childhood, with those men whom Heaven has chosen out to be distinguished and exalted above all others in our arts, for the reason that a good and beautiful manner can be acquired with the greatest facility by seeing the methods and works of men of excellence, not to mention that rivalry and emulation, as we have said elsewhere, have great power over our minds. Francesco Granacci, of whom we have already spoken, was one of those who were placed by the Magnificent Lorenzo de' Medici to learn in his garden; whence it happened that, recognizing, boy as he was, the great genius of Michelagnolo, and what extraordinary fruits he was likely to produce when full grown, he could never tear himself away from his side, and even strove with incredible attention and humility to be always following that great brain, insomuch that Michelagnolo was constrained to love him more than all his other friends, and to confide so much in him, that there was no one with whom he was more willing to confer touching his works or to share all that he knew of art at that time, than with Granacci. Then, after they had been companions together in the workshop of Domenico Ghirlandajo, it came to pass that Granacci, because he was held to be the best of Ghirlandajo's young men, the strongest draughtsman, and the one who had most grace in painting in distemper, assisted David and Benedetto Ghirlandajo, the brothers of Domenico, to finish the altar-piece of the high-altar in S. Maria Novella,  which had been left unfinished at the death of the same Domenico. By this work Granacci gained much experience, and afterwards he executed in the same manner as that altar-piece many pictures that are in the houses of citizens, and others which were sent abroad. And since he was very gracious, and made himself very useful in certain ceremonies that were performed in the city during the festivals of the Carnival, he was constantly employed by the Magnificent Lorenzo de' Medici in many similar works, and in particular for the masquerade that represented the Triumph of Paulus Emilius, which was held in honour of the victory that he gained over certain foreign nations. In this masquerade, which was full of most beautiful inventions, Granacci acquitted himself so well, although he was a mere lad, that he won the highest praise. And here I will not omit to tell that the same Lorenzo de' Medici, as I have said in another place, was the first inventor of those masquerades that represent some particular subject, and are called in Florence \"Canti\";[10] for it is not known that any were performed in earlier times.","label":[[44,53,"PER"],[170,173,"PER"],[179,185,"MYTH"],[253,256,"PRON"],[257,261,"PROD"],[380,385,"PROD"],[389,392,"PER"],[454,456,"PRON"],[500,503,"PRON"],[511,529,"PER"],[539,541,"PRON"],[603,633,"PER"],[627,633,"ORG"],[646,649,"PRON"],[650,656,"FAC"],[665,667,"PRON"],[696,699,"PER"],[703,705,"PRON"],[731,743,"PER"],[768,774,"PLANT"],[775,777,"PRON"],[817,819,"PRON"],[837,844,"PRON"],[855,858,"PRON"],[975,988,"PER"],[1012,1015,"PRON"],[1030,1033,"PRON"],[1040,1047,"PER"],[1075,1078,"PRON"],[1112,1114,"PRON"],[1151,1154,"PRON"],[1155,1160,"PROD"],[1182,1184,"PRON"],[1193,1196,"PROD"],[1221,1229,"PER"],[1243,1247,"PRON"],[1284,1292,"FAC"],[1296,1316,"PER"],[1339,1347,"PER"],[1357,1359,"PRON"],[1387,1398,"PER"],[1401,1410,"PER"],[1407,1410,"PER"],[1426,1437,"PER"],[1485,1494,"TECH"],[1505,1510,"PER"],[1515,1536,"PER"],[1542,1550,"PER"],[1554,1562,"PER"],[1564,1566,"TIME"],[1574,1627,"WORK"],[1578,1589,"PROD"],[1597,1607,"FAC"],[1611,1627,"FAC"],[1686,1694,"PER"],[1704,1708,"PROD"],[1709,1717,"PER"],[1757,1759,"PRON"],[1796,1807,"FAC"],[1813,1821,"PROD"],[1838,1844,"FAC"],[1848,1856,"PER"],[1903,1905,"PRON"],[1934,1941,"PRON"],[1965,1975,"EVE"],[2003,2007,"GPE"],[2019,2028,"EVE"],[2036,2044,"EVE"],[2046,2048,"PRON"],[2080,2110,"PER"],[2104,2110,"ORG"],[2127,2132,"PROD"],[2160,2170,"PROD"],[2192,2217,"MOTIF"],[2203,2217,"PER"],[2251,2258,"EVE"],[2264,2266,"PRON"],[2287,2302,"GPE"],[2295,2302,"GPE"],[2312,2322,"PROD"],[2357,2367,"PROD"],[2369,2377,"PER"],[2388,2395,"PRON"],[2414,2416,"PRON"],[2428,2431,"PER"],[2438,2440,"PRON"],[2474,2475,"PRON"],[2512,2530,"PER"],[2524,2530,"ORG"],[2535,2536,"PRON"],[2579,2587,"PER"],[2597,2608,"PROD"],[2667,2675,"GPE"],[2677,2682,"PROD"],[2693,2695,"PRON"]]}
{"id":694,"text":"In like manner Granacci was employed in the sumptuous and magnificent preparations that were made in the year 1513 for the entry of Pope Leo X, one of the Medici, by Jacopo Nardi, a man of great learning and most beautiful intellect, who, having been commanded by the Tribunal of Eight to prepare a splendid masquerade, executed a representation of the Triumph of Camillus.","label":[[15,23,"PER"],[101,114,"TIME"],[123,142,"TIME"],[155,161,"ORG"],[166,178,"PER"],[182,185,"PER"],[268,285,"ORG"],[308,318,"PROD"],[331,345,"PROD"],[353,372,"EVE"],[353,372,"MOTIF"],[364,372,"PER"]]}
{"id":695,"text":"He lived sixty-seven years, at the end of which he finished the course of his life after an ordinary malady, a kind of fever; and he was buried in the Church of S. Ambrogio at Florence, on the day of S. Andrew the Apostle, in 1544.","label":[[9,26,"TIME"],[151,157,"FAC"],[151,184,"FAC"],[161,172,"MYTH"],[176,184,"GPE"],[189,230,"TIME"],[200,221,"PER"],[214,221,"PER"]]}
{"id":696,"text":"But to come at length to some works by Granacci that are in existence, let me relate that, having studied the cartoon of Michelagnolo Buonarroti while the latter was executing it for the Great Hall of the Palace, he found it so instructive and made such proficience, that, when Michelagnolo was summoned to Rome by Pope Julius II to the end that he might paint the vaulting of the Chapel in his Palace, Granacci was one of the first to be sent for by Buonarroti to help him to paint that work in fresco after the cartoons that he himself had prepared.","label":[[30,35,"PROD"],[39,47,"PER"],[110,117,"PROD"],[121,144,"PER"],[187,197,"FAC"],[187,211,"FAC"],[205,211,"FAC"],[278,290,"PER"],[307,311,"GPE"],[315,319,"MYTH"],[315,329,"MYTH"],[361,387,"WORK"],[365,373,"FAC"],[381,387,"FAC"],[395,401,"FAC"],[403,411,"PER"],[451,461,"PER"],[488,492,"PROD"],[496,502,"TECH"],[513,521,"PROD"]]}
{"id":699,"text":"In Florence Granacci painted for Pier Francesco Borgherini a scene in oils on the head-board of a couch which stood in an apartment wherein Jacopo da Pontormo, Andrea del Sarto, and Francesco Ubertini had painted many stories from the life of Joseph, in Pier Francesco's house in Borgo Sant' Apostolo; and in this scene were little figures representing a story of the same Joseph, executed with extraordinary finish and with great charm and beauty of colouring, and a building in perspective, wherein he depicted Joseph ministering to Pharaoh, which could not be more beautiful in any part.","label":[[3,11,"GPE"],[12,20,"PER"],[33,58,"PER"],[59,589,"WORK"],[61,66,"PROD"],[70,74,"TECH"],[82,92,"PROD"],[98,103,"PROD"],[122,131,"FAC"],[140,158,"PER"],[150,158,"GPE"],[160,176,"PER"],[182,200,"PER"],[218,225,"PROD"],[218,300,"WORK"],[235,249,"MOTIF"],[235,249,"MYTH"],[243,249,"MYTH"],[254,268,"PER"],[271,276,"FAC"],[280,300,"GPE"],[286,300,"MYTH"],[314,319,"PROD"],[332,339,"PROD"],[355,360,"PROD"],[355,379,"MOTIF"],[373,379,"MYTH"],[468,476,"FAC"],[480,491,"TECH"],[513,519,"MYTH"],[513,542,"MOTIF"],[535,542,"MYTH"]]}
