{"id":660,"text":"And some of them, perceiving that Andrea was on the way to becoming known as an excellent painter, and being richer in spirit than in pocket, determined that he should paint round that cloister twelve pictures in chiaroscuro—that is to say, in fresco with terretta—containing twelve scenes from the life of S. John the Baptist.","label":[[34,40,"PER"],[90,97,"PER"],[185,193,"LOC"],[194,326,"WORK"],[201,209,"PROD"],[213,224,"TECH"],[244,250,"TECH"],[256,264,"MAT"],[283,289,"PROD"],[299,326,"MOTIF"],[299,326,"MYTH"],[307,326,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":659,"text":"But although it was proposed that some should be made every year, until such time as every city and district had one of its own, which would have produced a show of extraordinary magnificence, nevertheless this custom was abandoned in the year 1527.","label":[[91,95,"GPE"],[100,108,"GPE"],[211,217,"PROD"],[232,248,"TIME"]]}
{"id":658,"text":"After this, the Guild of Merchants determined to have some triumphal chariots made of wood after the manner of those of the ancient Romans, to the end that these might be drawn in procession on the morning of S. John's day, in place of certain altar-cloths and wax tapers which the cities and townships carry in token of tribute, passing before the Duke and the chief magistrates; and out of ten that were made at that time, Andrea painted some with scenes in oils and in chiaroscuro, which were much extolled.","label":[[16,21,"ORG"],[16,34,"ORG"],[25,34,"PER"],[69,77,"PROD"],[86,90,"MAT"],[132,138,"PER"],[194,205,"TIME"],[209,216,"MYTH"],[209,222,"TIME"],[244,256,"PROD"],[261,264,"MAT"],[265,271,"PROD"],[282,288,"GPE"],[293,302,"GPE"],[349,353,"PER"],[368,379,"PER"],[425,431,"PER"],[450,456,"PROD"],[460,464,"TECH"],[472,483,"TECH"]]}
{"id":657,"text":"At length, after the Lives of many craftsmen who have been excellent, some in colouring, some in drawing, and others in invention, we have come to the most excellent Andrea del Sarto, in whose single person nature and art demonstrated all that painting can achieve by means of draughtsmanship, colouring, and invention, insomuch that, if Andrea had possessed a little more fire and boldness of spirit, to correspond to his profound genius and judgment in his art, without a doubt he would have had no equal. But a certain timidity of spirit and a sort of humility and simplicity in his nature made it impossible that there should be seen in him that glowing ardour and that boldness which, added to his other qualities, would have made him truly divine in painting; for which reason he lacked those adornments and that grandeur and abundance of manners which have been seen in many other painters. His figures, however, for all their simplicity and purity, are well conceived, free from errors, and absolutely perfect in every respect. The expressions of his heads, both in children and in women, are gracious and natural, and those of men, both young and old, admirable in their vivacity and animation; his draperies are beautiful to a marvel, and his nudes very well conceived. And although his drawing is simple, all that he coloured is rare and truly divine. Andrea was born in Florence, in the year 1478, to a father who was all his life a tailor; whence he was always called Andrea del Sarto by everyone. Having come to the age of seven, he was taken away from his reading and writing school and apprenticed to the goldsmith's craft.","label":[[21,26,"PROD"],[35,44,"PER"],[78,87,"PROD"],[97,104,"PROD"],[131,133,"PRON"],[166,182,"PER"],[200,206,"PER"],[218,221,"PROD"],[244,252,"PROD"],[277,292,"PROD"],[294,303,"PROD"],[309,318,"PROD"],[338,344,"PER"],[419,422,"PRON"],[455,458,"PRON"],[459,462,"PROD"],[480,482,"PRON"],[582,585,"PRON"],[582,585,"PRON"],[641,644,"PRON"],[699,702,"PRON"],[736,739,"PRON"],[756,764,"PROD"],[783,785,"PRON"],[888,896,"PER"],[898,901,"PRON"],[902,909,"PROD"],[928,933,"PRON"],[1055,1058,"PRON"],[1074,1082,"PER"],[1090,1095,"PER"],[1136,1139,"PER"],[1174,1179,"PRON"],[1204,1207,"PRON"],[1208,1217,"PROD"],[1249,1252,"PRON"],[1253,1258,"PROD"],[1293,1296,"PRON"],[1297,1304,"PROD"],[1325,1327,"PRON"],[1363,1369,"PER"],[1382,1390,"GPE"],[1392,1408,"TIME"],[1415,1421,"PER"],[1434,1437,"PRON"],[1445,1451,"PER"],[1460,1462,"PRON"],[1481,1497,"PER"],[1537,1542,"TIME"],[1544,1546,"PRON"],[1567,1570,"PRON"],[1591,1597,"FAC"],[1621,1630,"PER"],[1633,1638,"PROD"]]}
{"id":662,"text":"Andrea then painted for Zanobi Girolami a picture with figures of no great size, wherein was a story of Joseph, the son of Jacob, which was finished by him with unremitting diligence, and therefore held to be a very beautiful painting.","label":[[0,6,"PER"],[24,39,"PER"],[40,234,"WORK"],[42,49,"PROD"],[55,62,"PROD"],[95,100,"PROD"],[95,128,"MOTIF"],[104,128,"MYTH"],[116,119,"PER"],[123,128,"MYTH"],[226,234,"PROD"]]}
{"id":661,"text":"Whereupon he was commissioned at the instance of Baccio d' Agnolo to paint in fresco, in a close on the steep path of Orsanmichele, which leads to the Mercato Nuovo, the Annunciation still to be seen there, executed on a minute scale, which brought him but little praise; and this may have been because Andrea, who worked well without over-exerting himself or forcing his powers, is believed to have tried in this work to force himself and to paint with too much care.","label":[[49,65,"PER"],[78,84,"TECH"],[110,114,"LOC"],[118,130,"GPE"],[151,164,"FAC"],[166,182,"WORK"],[170,182,"MOTIF"],[170,182,"MYTH"],[303,309,"PER"],[414,418,"PROD"]]}
