{"id":759,"text":"Francesco Maria being Duke of Urbino, there was born in the township of Sant'Agnolo in Vado, a place in that State, on the 1st of September in the year 1529, to the painter Ottaviano Zucchero, a male child to whom he gave the name of Taddeo; which boy having learned by the age of ten to read and write passing well, his father took him under his own discipline and taught him something of design. But, perceiving that his son had a very beautiful genius and was likely to become a better master in painting than he believed himself to be, Ottaviano placed him with Pompeo da Fano, who was very much his friend, but a commonplace painter. Pompeo's works not pleasing Taddeo, and likewise his ways, he returned to Sant'Agnolo, and there, as well as in other places, assisted his father to the best of his power and knowledge. Finally, being well grown in years and in judgment, and perceiving that he could not make much progress under the discipline of his father, who was burdened with seven sons and one daughter, and also that with his own little knowledge he could not be of as much assistance to his father as he might wish, he went off all alone, at the age of fourteen, to Rome. There, at first, not being known by anyone, and himself knowing no one, he suffered some hardships; and, if he did know one or two persons, he was treated worse by them than by the others. Thus, having approached Francesco, called Sant'Agnolo, who was working by the day at grotesques under Perino del Vaga, he commended himself to him with all humility, praying him that, being his kinsman, he should consent to help him; but no good came of it, for Francesco, as certain kinds of kinsmen often do, not only did not assist him by word or deed, but reproved and repelled him harshly. But for  all that, not losing heart and not being dismayed, the poor boy contrived to maintain himself (or we should rather say, to starve himself) for many months in Rome by grinding colours for a small price, now in one shop and now in another, at times also drawing something, as best he could.","label":[[0,15,"PER"],[0,36,"TIME"],[22,26,"PER"],[22,36,"PER"],[30,36,"GPE"],[60,114,"GPE"],[95,100,"GPE"],[109,114,"GPE"],[116,156,"TIME"],[165,191,"PER"],[200,205,"PER"],[214,216,"PRON"],[234,240,"PER"],[248,251,"PER"],[317,320,"PRON"],[321,327,"PER"],[333,336,"PRON"],[343,346,"PRON"],[373,376,"PRON"],[390,396,"PROD"],[419,422,"PRON"],[423,426,"PER"],[489,495,"PER"],[513,515,"PRON"],[525,532,"PRON"],[540,549,"PER"],[557,560,"PRON"],[566,580,"PER"],[576,580,"GPE"],[600,603,"PRON"],[604,610,"PER"],[630,637,"PER"],[639,645,"PER"],[648,653,"PROD"],[667,673,"PER"],[688,691,"PRON"],[698,700,"PRON"],[713,724,"GPE"],[774,777,"GPE"],[778,784,"PER"],[800,803,"PRON"],[897,899,"PRON"],[953,956,"PRON"],[957,963,"PER"],[993,997,"PER"],[1035,1038,"PRON"],[1060,1062,"PRON"],[1101,1104,"PRON"],[1105,1111,"PER"],[1115,1117,"MYTH"],[1130,1132,"PRON"],[1180,1184,"GPE"],[1234,1241,"PRON"],[1258,1260,"PRON"],[1294,1296,"PRON"],[1317,1324,"PER"],[1326,1328,"PRON"],[1350,1354,"PRON"],[1399,1428,"PER"],[1460,1470,"PROD"],[1477,1492,"PER"],[1494,1496,"PRON"],[1507,1514,"PRON"],[1518,1521,"PRON"],[1549,1552,"PRON"],[1565,1568,"PRON"],[1569,1576,"PER"],[1578,1580,"PRON"],[1604,1607,"PRON"],[1629,1631,"PRON"],[1637,1646,"PER"],[1668,1675,"PRON"],[1710,1713,"PRON"],[1757,1760,"PRON"],[1839,1842,"PER"],[1865,1872,"PRON"],[1909,1916,"PRON"],[1937,1941,"GPE"],[1992,1996,"FAC"],[2058,2060,"PRON"]]}
{"id":760,"text":"In the year 1548, therefore, when Taddeo had finished that work, he was vastly extolled by all Rome, and that with good reason, because after Polidoro, Maturino, Vincenzio da  San Gimignano, and Baldassarre da Siena, no one had attained in works of that kind to the standard that Taddeo had reached, who was then a young man only eighteen years of age.","label":[[0,16,"TIME"],[34,40,"PER"],[59,63,"PROD"],[95,99,"GPE"],[142,150,"PER"],[152,160,"PER"],[162,189,"PER"],[176,189,"GPE"],[195,215,"PER"],[210,215,"GPE"],[240,245,"PROD"],[280,286,"PER"],[321,324,"PER"],[330,344,"TIME"]]}
{"id":761,"text":"Maestro Mattivolo, the Master of the Post, bought in the time of Pope Julius a site on the Campo Marzio, and built there a large and very commodious house, and then commissioned Taddeo to paint the façade in chiaroscuro; which Taddeo executed there three stories of Mercury, the Messenger of the Gods, which were very beautiful, and the rest he caused to be painted by others after designs by his own hand.","label":[[0,7,"PER"],[0,41,"PER"],[23,29,"PER"],[37,41,"ORG"],[50,76,"TIME"],[65,69,"MYTH"],[65,76,"MYTH"],[91,103,"FAC"],[149,154,"FAC"],[178,184,"PER"],[198,204,"FAC"],[208,219,"TECH"],[227,233,"PER"],[255,262,"PROD"],[266,300,"MYTH"],[279,288,"PER"],[296,300,"MYTH"],[382,389,"PROD"]]}
{"id":762,"text":"In that work, which was on a groined vaulting, Taddeo painted the four Evangelists, two Sibyls, two Prophets, and four not very large stories of Jesus Christ and of the Virgin His Mother.","label":[[8,12,"PROD"],[37,45,"FAC"],[47,53,"PER"],[62,186,"WORK"],[66,83,"MYTH"],[66,108,"MOTIF"],[88,94,"MYTH"],[100,108,"MYTH"],[114,186,"MOTIF"],[134,141,"PROD"],[145,157,"MYTH"],[169,186,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":763,"text":"Meanwhile Taddeo painted in the Church of S. Ambrogio de' Milanesi, on the wall of the high-altar, four stories of the life of that Saint, coloured in fresco and not very large, with a frieze of little boys, and women after the manner of terminal figures; which was a work of no little beauty.","label":[[10,16,"PER"],[32,38,"FAC"],[32,66,"FAC"],[42,53,"MYTH"],[58,66,"PER"],[87,97,"FAC"],[99,254,"WORK"],[104,111,"PROD"],[104,137,"MOTIF"],[119,123,"PROD"],[132,137,"MYTH"],[151,157,"TECH"],[185,191,"PROD"],[195,254,"MOTIF"],[202,206,"PER"],[212,217,"PER"],[247,254,"PROD"],[268,272,"PROD"]]}
{"id":764,"text":"After that, Taddeo was ordered to repaint in the Sala de' Palafrenieri those Apostles which Raffaello had formerly executed there in terretta, and which had been thrown to the ground by Paul IV; and he, having painted one, caused all the others to be executed by his brother Federigo, who acquitted himself very well.","label":[[12,18,"PER"],[49,70,"FAC"],[77,85,"MOTIF"],[77,85,"MYTH"],[77,141,"WORK"],[92,101,"PER"],[133,141,"MAT"],[186,193,"MYTH"],[267,274,"PER"],[275,283,"PER"]]}
