{"id":754,"text":"Tiziano was born at Cadore, a little township situated on the Piave and five miles distant from the pass of the Alps, in the year 1480, from the family of the Vecelli, one of the most noble in that place. At the age of ten, having a fine spirit and a lively intelligence, he was sent to Venice to the house of an uncle, an honoured citizen, who, perceiving the boy to be much inclined to painting, placed him with Gian Bellini, an excellent painter very famous at that time, as has been related. Under his discipline, attending to design, he soon showed that he was endowed by nature with all the gifts of intellect and judgment that are necessary for the art of painting; and since at that time Gian Bellini and the other painters of that country, from not being able to study ancient works, were much—nay, altogether—given to copying from the life whatever work they did, and that with a dry, crude, and laboured manner, Tiziano also for a time learned that method. But having come to about the year 1507, Giorgione da Castelfranco, not altogether liking that mode of working, began to give to his pictures more softness and greater relief, with a beautiful manner; nevertheless he used to set himself before living and natural objects and counterfeit them as well as he was able with colours, and paint them broadly with tints crude or soft according as the life demanded, without doing any drawing, holding it as certain that to paint with colours only, without the study of drawing on paper, was the true and best method of working, and the true design. For he did not perceive that for him who wishes to distribute his compositions and accommodate his inventions well, it is necessary that he should first put them down on paper in several different ways, in order to see how  the whole goes together, for the reason that the idea is not able to see or imagine the inventions perfectly within herself, if she does not reveal and demonstrate her conception to the eyes of the body, that these may assist her to form a good judgment. Besides which, it is necessary to give much study to the nude, if you wish to comprehend it well, which you will never do, nor is it possible, without having recourse to paper; and to keep always before you, while you paint, persons naked or draped, is no small restraint, whereas, when you have formed your hand by drawing on paper, you then come little by little with greater ease to carry your conceptions into execution, designing and painting together. And so, gaining practice in art, you make both manner and judgment perfect, doing away with the labour and effort wherewith those pictures were executed of which we have spoken above, not to mention that by drawing on paper, you come to fill the mind with beautiful conceptions, and learn to counterfeit all the objects of nature by memory, without having to keep them always before you or being obliged to conceal beneath the glamour of colouring the painful fruits of your ignorance of design, in the manner that was followed for many years by the Venetian painters, Giorgione, Palma, Pordenone, and others, who never saw Rome or any other works of absolute perfection.","label":[[0,7,"PER"],[20,116,"GPE"],[37,45,"GPE"],[62,67,"GPE"],[100,104,"GPE"],[112,116,"GPE"],[118,134,"TIME"],[145,166,"ORG"],[272,274,"PRON"],[287,293,"GPE"],[313,318,"PER"],[332,339,"PER"],[361,364,"PER"],[388,396,"PROD"],[405,408,"PRON"],[414,473,"PER"],[441,448,"PER"],[502,505,"PRON"],[531,537,"PROD"],[539,541,"PRON"],[559,561,"PRON"],[559,561,"PRON"],[577,583,"GPE"],[656,659,"PROD"],[663,671,"PROD"],[696,708,"PER"],[723,731,"PER"],[740,747,"GPE"],[786,791,"PROD"],[859,863,"PROD"],[864,868,"PRON"],[923,930,"PER"],[993,1006,"TIME"],[1008,1033,"PER"],[1021,1033,"GPE"],[1096,1099,"PRON"],[1100,1108,"PROD"],[1181,1183,"PRON"],[1196,1203,"PRON"],[1254,1258,"PRON"],[1270,1272,"PRON"],[1306,1310,"PRON"],[1411,1413,"PRON"],[1490,1495,"MAT"],[1551,1557,"PROD"],[1563,1565,"PRON"],[1592,1595,"PRON"],[1621,1624,"PRON"],[1625,1637,"PROD"],[1654,1657,"PRON"],[1658,1668,"PROD"],[1675,1677,"PRON"],[1696,1698,"PRON"],[1729,1734,"MAT"],[1871,1881,"PROD"],[1899,1906,"PRON"],[1911,1914,"PRON"],[1947,1950,"PRON"],[2053,2055,"PRON"],[2095,2099,"PROD"],[2104,2107,"PRON"],[2127,2129,"PRON"],[2142,2145,"PRON"],[2168,2170,"PRON"],[2208,2213,"MAT"],[2241,2244,"PRON"],[2252,2255,"PRON"],[2263,2270,"PER"],[2325,2328,"PRON"],[2372,2375,"PRON"],[2430,2434,"PRON"],[2524,2527,"PROD"],[2529,2532,"PRON"],[2626,2634,"PROD"],[2658,2660,"PRON"],[2714,2719,"MAT"],[2721,2724,"PRON"],[2819,2825,"GPE"],[2879,2882,"PRON"],[2956,2962,"PLANT"],[2966,2970,"PRON"],[2984,2990,"PROD"],[3046,3054,"PER"],[3055,3063,"PER"],[3065,3074,"PER"],[3076,3081,"PER"],[3083,3092,"PER"],[3120,3124,"GPE"],[3138,3143,"PROD"]]}
{"id":755,"text":"And in the year when Andrea Gritti was elected Doge, Tiziano painted his portrait,  which was a very rare thing, in a picture wherein are Our Lady, S. Mark, and S. Andrew with the countenance of that Doge; which picture, a most marvellous work, is in the Sala del Collegio.","label":[[4,51,"TIME"],[53,60,"PER"],[73,81,"PROD"],[116,272,"WORK"],[118,125,"PROD"],[138,146,"MYTH"],[138,204,"MOTIF"],[148,155,"MYTH"],[161,170,"MYTH"],[200,204,"PER"],[212,219,"PROD"],[239,243,"PROD"],[255,272,"FAC"]]}
{"id":756,"text":"Then in the year 1507, while the Emperor Maximilian was making war on the Venetians, Tiziano, according to his own account, painted an Angel Raphael with Tobias and a dog in the Church of S. Marziliano, with a distant landscape, where, in a little wood, S. John the Baptist is praying on his knees to Heaven, whence comes a radiance that illumines him; and this work it is thought that he executed before he made a beginning with the façade of the Fondaco de' Tedeschi.","label":[[5,83,"TIME"],[33,40,"PER"],[33,51,"PER"],[63,66,"EVE"],[63,83,"EVE"],[74,83,"PER"],[85,92,"PER"],[132,468,"WORK"],[135,140,"MYTH"],[135,148,"MYTH"],[135,351,"MOTIF"],[154,160,"MYTH"],[167,170,"ANIM"],[178,184,"FAC"],[178,201,"FAC"],[188,201,"MYTH"],[218,227,"GPE"],[248,252,"MAT"],[254,273,"MYTH"],[301,307,"MYTH"],[362,366,"PROD"],[434,440,"FAC"],[448,468,"FAC"]]}
{"id":757,"text":"Afterwards, having gone to Vicenza, Tiziano painted the Judgment of Solomon in fresco, which was a beautiful work, under the little loggia where justice is administered in public audience.","label":[[27,34,"GPE"],[36,43,"PER"],[52,187,"WORK"],[56,75,"MOTIF"],[56,75,"MYTH"],[79,85,"TECH"],[109,113,"PROD"],[132,138,"FAC"],[145,152,"PROD"]]}
