{"id":741,"text":"Although it appears in a certain sense impossible that one who imitates some man excellent in our arts, and follows in his footsteps, should not become in great measure like him, nevertheless it may be seen that very often the brothers and sons of persons of singular ability do not follow their kinsmen in this respect, but fall away strangely from their standard. Which comes to pass, I think, not because there are not in them, through their blood, the same fiery spirit and the same genius, but rather from another reason—that is, from overmuch ease and comfort and from an over-abundance of means, which often prevent men from becoming industrious and assiduous in their studies. Yet this rule is not so fixed that the contrary does not sometimes happen. David and Benedetto Ghirlandajo, although they had very good parts and could have followed their brother Domenico in the matters of art, yet did not do so, for the reason that after the death of that same brother they strayed away from the path of good work, one of them, Benedetto, spending a long time as a wanderer, and the other distilling his brains away vainly in the study of mosaic. David, who had been much beloved by Domenico, and who loved him equally, both living and dead, finished after his death, in company with his brother Benedetto, many works begun by Domenico, and in particular the altar-piece of the high-altar in S. Maria Novella, that is, the part at the back, which now faces the choir; and some pupils of the same Domenico finished the predella in little figures, Niccolaio painting with great diligence, below the figure of S. Stephen, a disputation of that Saint, while Francesco Granacci, Jacopo  del Tedesco, and Benedetto executed the figures of S. Antonino, Archbishop of Florence, and S. Catharine of Siena. And they painted an altar-picture of S. Lucia that is in that place, with the head of a friar, near the centre of the church; and many other paintings and pictures that are in the houses of various individuals. After having been several years in France, where he worked and earned not a little, Benedetto returned to Florence with many privileges and presents that he had received from that King in testimony of his talents.","label":[[9,11,"PRON"],[77,80,"PER"],[98,102,"PROD"],[119,122,"PRON"],[174,177,"PRON"],[192,194,"PRON"],[227,235,"PER"],[240,244,"PER"],[248,255,"PER"],[290,295,"PRON"],[296,303,"PER"],[350,355,"PRON"],[387,388,"PRON"],[425,429,"PRON"],[623,626,"PER"],[760,765,"PER"],[770,791,"PER"],[851,856,"PRON"],[857,864,"PER"],[865,873,"PER"],[892,895,"PROD"],[965,972,"PER"],[1000,1004,"LOC"],[1013,1017,"PROD"],[1032,1041,"PER"],[1069,1077,"PER"],[1104,1107,"PRON"],[1143,1149,"PROD"],[1151,1156,"PER"],[1187,1195,"PER"],[1211,1214,"PRON"],[1261,1264,"PRON"],[1288,1291,"PRON"],[1292,1299,"PER"],[1300,1309,"PER"],[1316,1321,"PROD"],[1331,1339,"PER"],[1359,1412,"WORK"],[1363,1374,"PROD"],[1382,1392,"FAC"],[1396,1412,"FAC"],[1465,1470,"FAC"],[1481,1487,"PER"],[1500,1508,"PER"],[1522,1530,"FAC"],[1541,1548,"PROD"],[1550,1559,"PER"],[1601,1607,"PROD"],[1601,1621,"WORK"],[1611,1621,"MYTH"],[1623,1650,"WORK"],[1625,1636,"MYTH"],[1625,1650,"MOTIF"],[1645,1650,"MYTH"],[1658,1676,"PER"],[1678,1697,"PER"],[1703,1712,"PER"],[1726,1733,"PROD"],[1737,1772,"MYTH"],[1737,1772,"WORK"],[1750,1760,"MYTH"],[1764,1772,"GPE"],[1778,1799,"MYTH"],[1778,1799,"WORK"],[1794,1799,"GPE"],[1805,1809,"PRON"],[1821,1834,"PROD"],[1821,1925,"WORK"],[1838,1846,"MOTIF"],[1838,1846,"MYTH"],[1870,1894,"MOTIF"],[1889,1894,"MYTH"],[1919,1925,"FAC"],[1942,1951,"PROD"],[1956,1964,"PROD"],[1981,1987,"FAC"],[1999,2010,"PER"],[2047,2053,"GPE"],[2061,2063,"PRON"],[2096,2105,"PER"],[2118,2126,"GPE"],[2166,2168,"PRON"],[2192,2196,"PER"],[2213,2216,"PRON"]]}
{"id":742,"text":"That Nunziata, although he was a puppet-painter, was in some things a person of distinction, and above all in preparing fireworks and the girandole that were made every year for the festival of S. John; and, since he was an amusing and facetious person, everyone took great pleasure in conversing with him.","label":[[5,13,"FAC"],[33,47,"PER"],[70,76,"PER"],[120,129,"PROD"],[138,147,"PROD"],[178,201,"TIME"],[246,252,"PER"]]}
{"id":743,"text":"Now those works were executed by that painter while his uncle David was still alive, and that good old man took the greatest pleasure in them, thanking God that he had lived so long as to see the art of Domenico come to life again, as it were, in Ridolfo.","label":[[10,15,"PROD"],[38,45,"PER"],[56,61,"PER"],[62,67,"PER"],[103,106,"PER"],[152,155,"MYTH"],[196,199,"PROD"],[203,211,"PER"],[247,254,"PER"]]}
{"id":744,"text":"Ridolfo was a rapid and resolute painter in certain kinds of work, and particularly in festive decorations; and thus, for the entry of the Emperor Charles V into Florence, he executed in ten days an arch at the Canto alla Cuculia, and another arch in a very short time at the Porta al Prato for the coming of the most illustrious Lady, Duchess Leonora, as will be related in the Life of Battista Franco.","label":[[0,7,"PER"],[33,40,"PER"],[61,65,"PROD"],[122,170,"TIME"],[139,146,"PER"],[139,156,"PER"],[162,170,"GPE"],[184,195,"TIME"],[199,203,"FAC"],[211,229,"FAC"],[243,247,"FAC"],[276,290,"FAC"],[330,334,"PER"],[330,351,"PER"],[336,343,"PER"],[379,383,"PROD"],[387,402,"PER"]]}
{"id":745,"text":"For the Convent of the Nuns of Ripoli Ridolfo painted two altar-pieces in oils: in one the Coronation of Our Lady, and in the other a Madonna surrounded by certain Saints.","label":[[8,15,"FAC"],[8,37,"FAC"],[23,27,"MYTH"],[31,37,"GPE"],[38,45,"PER"],[58,70,"PROD"],[74,78,"TECH"],[87,113,"WORK"],[91,113,"MOTIF"],[91,113,"MYTH"],[105,113,"MYTH"],[132,170,"WORK"],[134,141,"MYTH"],[134,170,"MOTIF"],[164,170,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":746,"text":"Ridolfo had a brother called Don Bartolommeo in the Angeli, a seat of the Monks of Camaldoli in Florence, who was a truly religious, upright, and worthy man; and Ridolfo, who loved him much, painted for him in the cloister that opens into the garden—that is, in the loggia where there are the stories of S. Benedict painted in verdaccio by the hand of Paolo Uccello, on the right hand as one enters by the door of the garden—a scene in which that same Saint, seated at table with two Angels beside him, is waiting for bread to be sent for him into the grotto by Romanus, but the Devil has cut the cord with stones; and the same Saint investing a young man with the habit.","label":[[0,7,"PER"],[29,44,"PER"],[52,104,"FAC"],[62,66,"FAC"],[74,92,"MYTH"],[96,104,"GPE"],[153,156,"PER"],[162,169,"PER"],[214,222,"FAC"],[243,249,"FAC"],[266,272,"FAC"],[289,424,"WORK"],[293,300,"PROD"],[293,315,"MOTIF"],[304,315,"MYTH"],[352,365,"PER"],[406,410,"FAC"],[418,424,"FAC"],[425,613,"WORK"],[427,432,"PROD"],[447,613,"MOTIF"],[452,457,"MYTH"],[469,474,"PROD"],[484,490,"PROD"],[552,558,"GPE"],[562,569,"MYTH"],[579,584,"MYTH"],[597,601,"PROD"],[607,613,"MAT"],[623,670,"MOTIF"],[623,670,"WORK"],[628,633,"MYTH"],[652,655,"PER"],[665,670,"MYTH"]]}
{"id":747,"text":"At the Madonna di Vertigli, a seat of the Monks of Camaldoli, without the township of Monte Sansovino, Ridolfo, having with him the above-named Battista Franco and Michele, executed in chiaroscuro, in a little cloister, all the stories of the life of Joseph; in the church, the altar-pieces of the high-altar, and a Visitation of Our Lady in fresco, which is as beautiful as any work in fresco that Ridolfo ever painted.","label":[[7,101,"FAC"],[30,34,"FAC"],[42,60,"MYTH"],[74,101,"GPE"],[103,110,"PER"],[144,159,"PER"],[164,171,"PER"],[185,196,"TECH"],[210,218,"FAC"],[224,257,"WORK"],[228,235,"PROD"],[228,257,"MOTIF"],[243,257,"MYTH"],[251,257,"MYTH"],[266,272,"FAC"],[278,290,"PROD"],[298,308,"FAC"],[314,419,"WORK"],[316,338,"MOTIF"],[316,338,"MYTH"],[330,338,"MYTH"],[342,348,"TECH"],[379,383,"PROD"],[387,393,"TECH"],[399,406,"PER"]]}
